--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
字幕翻译：CMCT字幕组 后期处理：不死别姬
你在胡说八道
You're not saying things that mean anything.
这算是讨论问题？ 我告诉你，这辆车就是更好
It's not even a debate. It's a better automobile!
别对我胡说什么林肯比凯迪拉克好
Ain't no way you can say to me a Lincoln is better than a Cadillac.
- 林肯就是更好  - 得了吧
- A Lincoln is better. It's a better automobile. - Forget about it.
卡迪拉克的提速快，马力也更足
A Cadillac's got more acceleration. It's got more power.
操控性也更好
It's got better handling.
空间也很大，它的马力也更足
It's got more legroom for your legs. It's got more power.
- 这点你已经说过了  - 不错
- You just said that. - Bingo.
- 怎么了？  - 你已经说过马力更足了
- What? - You just said, "More power."
- 你在开始重复你自己的话了  - 我是那样说的吗？
- You're starting to repeat yourself. - I said that?
- 你是老了  - 那可要怪他
- You're getting senile. - He got me so fucking aggravated.
要我说，梅塞德斯比它们都要好
I'll tell you one thing, Mercedes got it all over both of them.
梅塞德斯奔驰？
A Mercedes?
开林肯的感觉就像在开一个该死的水床
A Lincoln's like driving a fucking water bed, for Christ's sakes.
- 奔驰  - 是啊，奔驰是好车
- A Mercedes. - Yeah. It's a good car.
让我告诉你，伙计，不要怀疑，林肯更长些
I'll tell you one thing, my friend. Undisputable. The Lincoln is longer.
它更长？比谁更长？比我下面更长？
It's longer? Longer like what? Longer like my dick is longer?
不不不，我们不是在说大众
No, no, no. We're not talking about a Volkswagen.
什么？大众
What do you mean? Yeah, Volkswagen.
更长，一英寸长也是更长
Longer. Like longer. Like in inches it's longer.
- 你在胡说八道什么  - 这车更长
- You don't make no fucking sense. - It's a longer car.
两辆他妈的小车，好吧？ 这是一辆，这是一辆，对吗？
Two fucking cars, right? This is a car, this is a car, right?
在这里好不好？
Right here, okay?
如果所有条件都一样，那更长的会先达到目的
All things being equal, the one's longer gonna get there first.
这点不需要爱因斯坦般的智慧就能理解吧
You don't have to be fucking Einstein to understand this.
你知道当你达到以后会发生什么？
You know what happens when you get there, don't you?
- 不  - 那你还是去开那该死的林肯吧
- No. - You're still driving a fucking Lincoln.
我要给你看一张示意图，是两辆车 更长的那辆先到达目的
I'll show you a fucking picture. Two cars. The one's longer gets there first.
这是客观事实，这辆更长
That's a scientific fact. It's a longer car.
- 我能问一些事吗？  - 问什么？
- Can I ask you guys something? - What?
你们是那种聪明的家伙吗？
Are you guys, you know, wise guys?
聪明的家伙？什么是聪明的家伙？
Wise guys? What are wise guys?
- 你知道是什么  - 为什么觉得我们是头目？
- You know... - What makes you think we're wise guys?
我们可能是警察
We could be cops.
确实
Yeah.
- 你觉得我，便衣？  - 不，我没有
- You believed me. Undercover what? - No, I didn't.
- 你相信过我  - 不，只是…
- You believed me. - No, it's just...
- 那人是谁？ - 哪个？
- Who's that over there? - Who?
吧台那边，留个小胡子的
The guy by the bar with the mustache.
那是唐，珠宝商，基利带来的
That's Don, Don the Jeweler. Jilly brought him here.
基利？那个四眼？
What Jilly? Jilly "Four-eyes"?
不是四眼基利，他是从昆士来的
Not that fucking hump Jilly "Four-eyes." Jilly, you know, from Queens.
- 你觉得他聪明吗？  - 不，他只是跑腿的
- You think he's a wise guy? - No, he's a connected guy.
跑腿？那要是我脱手，他能帮我吗？
Connected? If I had a thing to lay off, he could lay it off for me?
- 你怎么想不干了？  - 不是这个意思
- You got something you gotta lay off? - Ain't the question.
- 你有东西要卖？  - 不管你的事
我只是说，他是否能从我这收货，只是假设
I'm just saying if I had a thing, he could lay it off. That's all.
你欠这么多债，想退休你得先去劫辆运钞车
All that fucking money you owe downtown, you'd have to lay off a fucking Brink's truck.
- 桑尼有伴了  - 我看有伴了的是“左撇子”老左吧
- Sonny's in love. - I think fucking Lefty's in love.
再见
I'll see you.
你睡了吗？
Were you asleep?
- 你还好吗？宝贝  - 我没事
- Are you okay, honey? - Yeah, I'm okay.
去睡吧，我明天再打电话给你
Go back to sleep. I'll call you tomorrow.
那好，宝贝
That's good, babe.
好的，很抱歉我要睡了，我好困
Okay. I'm sorry. I gotta go back to sleep. I'm so tired.
- 好的  - 好的
- All right. - All right.
- 喂  - 嗯？
- Hey. - Yeah.
什么？
What?
把电话放在枕边
Put the phone on your pillow.
我要听你的呼吸声
I want to listen to you breathe.
你是珠宝商唐吗？
You Don the Jeweler?
这儿有些上等货色
There. That's some beautiful thing.
干嘛不给你老婆？
Why don't you give it to your wife?
我老婆？我怎么能给我老婆？
My wife? How am I gonna give it to my wife?
- 我没结婚  - 女朋友呢？
- I ain't married. - Got a girlfriend?
- 有个女友  - 那就娶了她
- Yeah, I got a girlfriend. - So marry her.
嘿，你是认真的吗？
Hey, you for real?
我想请你看看中间那颗钻石
I'm asking you to middle a diamond for me here.
- 看看它值不值八千块  - 我建议…
- All I want from my end is $8,000. - And I'm saying to you
你最好把它送给不懂的人，这是A货
is you should give it to somebody that don't know better, because that's a fugazy.
好吗？
All right?
它是A货？你怎么知道？
That's a fugazy? How do you know it's a fugazy?
- 你就看了一眼  - 怎么？是假货
- You looked at it for two seconds. - What? It's a fake.
我知道A货是什么意思
I know what a fugazy is.
喂，老兄，想开开眼吗？
Hey, pal, you want to see something?
我让你看看吧
I'm gonna show you something.
你看，不错吧？你看多漂亮
There you go. Ain't that something? That's a beautiful thing.
是漂亮，可惜不是我的
Yeah, that is a beautiful thing, but it's not my thing.
我这个呢？
What about this?
我说什么好呢？想法脱手吧
What do you want me to say? Go ahead, try and sell it,
够爷们的话就把它打碎了
you want to be a dumbsky. Give it a shot.
够爷们？你要我够爷们？
Dumbsky? You calling me a dumbsky?
知道你在跟谁说话吗？
You know who you're talking to, my friend?
嗨，老左，来啊，来喝一杯汽酒
Hey, Left. Come on, have a spritzer.
你不会是想拿着这东西去丢人吧
You want to go embarrass yourself with this thing...
丢人？我的家人，我的孩子
Embarrass myself? My family, my children...
我的母亲，她们走在附近任何街上的时候
My mother can hold her head up in any neighborhood in this city
都能抬头挺胸？明白吗？
when she walks down the block, see?
全部的五个区的人，都认识我 这可以不提了
In all the five boroughs, I'm known. Forget about it.
全世界的人都他妈认识我
I'm known all over the fucking world.
谁不认识我老左，去慕伯尼街问问
Anybody, ask anybody about Lefty from Mulberry Street.
- 你惹了不该惹的人物了  - 我并非想冒犯你
- You're pissing up the wrong fucking tree. - I didn't mean no disrespect.
- 这是一个误会  - 你去哪儿？你坐下
- It's a misunderstanding. - Where you going? Sit down there.
你想甩开我吗？
You're gonna walk out on me?
只能我甩开你，你甩不开我
You don't walk out on me. I walk out on you.
- 你有车吗？ - 有车
- You got a car? - I got a car.
那我搭你的车，走吧
Let's go get your car. Come on.
走好
Take care.
把窗关上，我吹的不爽
Put that window up. I'm gonna catch a draft.
我他妈要在这里得上癌症了
I'm getting fucking cancer over here.
- 你会没事的  - 我们要去哪儿？
- You'll be all right. - Where we going?
你是警察吗？别他妈问来问去的
You a cop? Don't ask so many fucking questions.
好吧，我得教教你，伙计，我得教教你
Well, well, I've got to school you, my friend. I've got to school you.
搞什么？你为基利工作，他从没教你？
What's the matter? You work for Jilly, he never school you?
教我什么？
School me in what?
我说话时别插嘴
You don't talk until I talk to you.
A货
Fugazy.
你说那个戒指是A货，你他妈就是一文盲
You call that ring a fugazy. You don't know word fucking one, my friend.
我知道什么是文盲，看着你我就知道了
I know. I look at you and I know.
你这家伙就不能闭上你的嘴
You a guy can't keep his fucking mouth shut.
嘿，我正说你呢
Hey, I'm talking to you now.
我做珠宝生意五年了
Look, I've been in jewels five years.
你说我要是连他妈锆石和钻石都分不出来
How do you figure I'm gonna earn the kind of money I do
我还赚屁个钱啊！
if I can't tell a fucking zircon?
- 这行有钱可赚？  - 什么？
- There's good money in it? - What?
什么？
What?
- 什么？珠宝业？ - 谢谢
- What, jewels? - Thank you.
是啊，如果你懂行的话，有赚头
Yeah. If you know what you're doing, there is.
我们去23大街8号吧 看看你是不是有两把刷子
Let's go to 23rd and 8th. Then we'll find out if you know what you're doing.
你欠我八千块
You owe me $8,000.
不，等等，我给你钻石
No, hold on. Wait. I gave you the diamond.
老左，这人是谁？
Left, who's this guy?
- 他说这是A的  - 什么是A的？
- He says it's a fugazy. - What's a fugazy?
- 钻石是A的  - A是什么？
- Your diamond's a fugazy. - What is a fugazy?
- 得了，你知道的  - 不要告诉我该知道什么
- Come on, you know. - Don't you tell me what I know.
- 你心里有数，伙计  - 你们中有一个弄错了
- You know what you did, pal. - One of you has got to be wrong.
那是一颗蒂梵尼的钻石
That's a Tiffany fucking diamond.
老左，那是我老婆的钻戒
Left, that is my wife's fucking diamond ring.
可惜是A货的，老左
It's a fugazy, Left.
你拿走你老婆的戒指？
You took away your wife's ring?
听着，你带着戒指去第47大道问问
Look, you bring that ring to any kike on 47th Street,
他会告诉你那是顶级的钻石
he's gonna tell you that that is primo.
你要拿你老婆的戒指去赌运气？
You took away your wife's ring to go bet on the Giants?
嘿，听着，你已经不想要它了 把它还给我，好吧？
Hey, look, you don't want it. Give it back to me, okay?
- 嘿，老左，给我  - 8000元
- Hey, Left, come on... - $8,000.
让我跟这混蛋单独谈谈，就半秒，可以吧？
Let me talk to this fucking guy for a second. Just give me half a second, would you?
8000元
$8,000.
干嘛不去吧台喝一杯？
Why don't you go to the bar and have a drink?
我跟他谈几句，去吧
Let me talk to the guy for a minute. Come on.
嘿，我他妈可是黑带…你
Hey, I got a fucking black belt, pal. So you...
干！
Shit!
他会宰了你，懂吗？
This guy is going to fucking kill you. You understand what I'm saying?
我们只有两分钟的时间
We got about two minutes to figure a way out of this thing.
- 对不起  - 对不起？你给我住嘴！
- I'm sorry. - You're sorry? Shut the fuck up.
- 说对不起有屁用  - 我不想死！
- Sorry ain't gonna do it. - I don't want to die.
是吗？
Yeah?
- 你开的什么车？  - 保时捷
- What kind of car do you drive? - A Porsche.
把锁匙给我
Give me the keys.
拿去
All right.
- 现在它是谁的？ - 是老左的
- Whose car is it now? - It's Lefty's.
它归老左了，对
Lefty's stuff. All right, good.
伙计，拿去喝一杯
That's for the fucking drinks, pal.
你干嘛给他钱，唐？聪明人不会这样的
Why'd you pay for that drink, Don? A wise guy never pays for a drink.
- 我不知道  - 总是别人买单？
- I didn't know that. - Always on the arm.
好吧
All right.
你还是把他吓坏了
You scared that guy, though.
真是笑死我了
That cracks me up.
我一共做过26个人 可他们居然怕的是你，干
I got 26 fucking hits under my belt, and you're the one he's scared of. Fuck.
- 靠边  - 什么？
- Pull over. - What?
靠边，我要拿些东西
Pull over. I've got to do something.
- 这里吗？ - 是的，这里，靠边
- Right here? - Yeah. Right here, pull over.
好吧，我有点冷了
All right. I'm cool.
来，帮一下我，把这个拉出来，拉
Come on, give me a hand with this. Pull this out, pull it.
- 你把东西都拆散了  - 你没听到仪表盘下有声音？
- You're taking the whole fucking thing apart. - You didn't hear nothing under the dash?
- 我什么都没听到  - 是这儿
- No, I didn't hear a fucking thing. - There it is.
我能装回去的
I can go right up the back.
你在搞什么鬼？
What the fuck are you doing down there?
- 这里有点问题  - 你认为有窃听器吗？
- Just feeling around here. - You think I got a wire in my car?
- 干！ - 当我是傻瓜吗？
- Fuck! - You think I'm fucking stupid?
我说过吗？我说了你有窃听器的吗？
Did I say that? Did I say you got a wire?
那你当着我面这样做
Say it to my face, if you're gonna do this.
算了，不过你得向我道歉
Nothing for nothing, but I think you owe me an apology.
这倒不是问题 问题是我掉了把螺丝刀在这里
Ain't the question. I lost a screwdriver here.
- 什么？ - 螺丝刀掉下去了
- You lost a what? - The screwdriver fell down there.
天啊！你掉把螺丝刀在我音响里面？
Come on. You lost a screwdriver in my fucking stereo?
你记得把它取出来，就在下面
You'll find it again. It's down there.
- 你喜欢凯迪拉克Deville？  - 得了吧
- So you like the DeVille? - Forget about it.
我有一辆凯迪拉克Fleetwood Brougham
Yeah. I got the Fleetwood Brougham.
- 是吗？有丝织坐垫的吗？  - 得了吧
- Is that right? With the velour? - Forget about it.
- 结婚了吗？ - 没
- Are you married? - No.
- 我有个女友在加州  - 真好
- I got a girl out there in California. - That's good.
她应该呆在那儿
She should stay in California.
就不会整天监视着你裤裆了
Keep your eye out for your balls.
- 对，说得对 - 我一向是对的
- Yeah, you're right. - I'm always right.
聪明人总是对的，什么时候都是
A wise guy's always right. Even when he's wrong, he's right.
道上的说法，跑腿的先做头目 然后做心腹，最后做老大
All the way up the line, connected guy to wise guy to skipper to boss.
- 是的，我懂 - 你懂？
- Yeah, I know that. - You know?
- 是啊  - 你懂什么？
- Yeah. - What do you know?
就像…军队里的军衔关系
It's kind of like the army, like a chain of command.
军队？一点都不像军队
The army? It ain't nothing like the army.
军队里是一帮你全都不了解的家伙
The army is some guy you don't know
要你干掉另一帮你不了解的家伙 这才是军队
sends you out to whack some other guy you don't know. Army.
- 明天跟我去看看吗？ - 好，好的
- You want to check in with me tomorrow? - Yeah, all right.
不知你是怎样看出那戒指真假的
I don't know how the fuck you knew that ring was a fugazy.
- 明天见  - 好，再见
- I'll see you tomorrow. - Yeah, so long.
珠宝商唐是个好商人，但不会赚大钱
Don the Jeweler is a good earner. He ain't a leech.
他很本份，只是个珠宝商
He keeps to himself. He's a jewel guy.
- 他从哪儿来的，基利？ - 佛罗里达
- Where's he from, Jilly? - Florida.
- 佛罗里达 - 是个珠宝商
- Florida. - He's a jewel guy.
- 具体是哪里？是海边吗？ - 不，不是海边
- But Florida where? The beach? - No, not the beach.
我…我也太不清楚
I don't know.
不知道是不是道格春训的地方
Wherever the fuck the Dodgers have spring training.
靠得住吗？
He's a stand-up guy?
我只是认识他，老左，又没和他上过床
I said I knew him, Left. I didn't say I fucked him.
嘿，你，过来！
Hey, you. Come here!
过来
Come here.
你说什么，基利？什么事？
What do you say, Jilly? How you doing?
我朋友老左问起你，别丢我的脸，知道？
My friend Lefty's asking about you. Don't embarrass me, capisce?
我不会的，你知道的，基利
I wouldn't do that to you. You know that, Jilly.
对，不然的话我们就把你给做了
Because if you do, one of us is gonna whack you out.
那可不怎么好啊
That's not good.
基利，坐回去吧
All right, Jilly. Go back to your bath.
- 保重，孩子  - 你也保重
- Take care, kid. - Good to see you.
好了，我介绍你时
When I introduce you, I'm gonna say,
我会说“你是我的一个朋友” 意思就是说你是我小弟
"This is a friend of mine." That means you're a connected guy.
如我改称你为“我们的朋友” 意思是说你是有点来头的
If I said instead, "This is a friend of ours," that would mean you're a made guy.
懂了么？
Capisce?
我的朋友，我们的朋友
Yeah, "friend of mine." "Friend of ours."
- 那我怎么称呼你呢？我们的朋友？  - 你别提起我
- What do I call you? "Friend of ours," or... - You keep your mouth shut about me.
懂了吗？唐
Know what I'm saying? Hey, Don.
你带钱了吗？
You got a couple of fazools?
- 我有点事情，急用  - 了解
- I got some things I got to take care of. - Yeah.
需要多少，一百？
What do you want? $100?
这算什么？
What are you doing?
聪明人是不这样放钱的
A wise guy don't carry his money in a wallet.
他会把钱卷起来，像这样
A wise guy carries money in a roll. Like this. See?
正面朝外，就这样，走吧
Beaner on the outside. Like that. Come on.
你那胡须
That mustache.
去剃了吧，那是不允许的
You got to get rid of that mustache, 'cause that's against the rules.
去买条裤子，别跟牛仔似的
And get a pair of pants, will you? This ain't a fucking rodeo.
要穿得像我一样，这是我家
Dress like I dress. This is my family.
- 比我自己家更像我家  - 这样可以吗？
- More even than my own family. - Is that right?
- 我没有家 - 你没有家？
- I don't got a family. - You don't got a family?
我是孤儿，我在孤儿院长大的
No, I'm an orphan. I grew up in an orphanage.
别担心，没事，就把它当自己家
Ain't the question, even if you had a family.
你觉得它是你家，它就是你的家了
If this is your family, then this is your family.
- 懂我意思吗？  - 懂
- You know what I'm saying? - Yeah.
我蛋蛋都快冻掉了
I'm freezing my balls off.
这么冷整天呆在外面干嘛？
What do we got to be standing outside all day in the cold for?
- 我们当标志杆  - 南极的标志杆
- Got to show the flag. - The flag of fucking Antarctica.
- 你们去哪儿？  - 嘿，老左
- What's going on? - Hey, Lefty.
- 嘿，左兄，忙啥呢？ - 这是唐尼，我的朋友
- Lefty, what do you say? - This is Donnie, a friend of mine.
你好
How you doing?
我那东西都成冰棍了
The good news is my dick is now a popsicle.
- 嘿，桑尼 - 嘿，桑尼，你好
- Hi, Sonny. - Hey, Sonny, how you doing?
红桑尼
Sonny Red.
- 这人是谁？  - 这是唐尼，是我的朋友
- Who's this guy? - This is Donnie, a friend of mine.
他看起来很危险
Just stand there and look dangerous, friend.
他看上去很危险，真的吗？
He does look dangerous, don't he?
这周钱交了吗？但愿如此
You gonna make this week's vig? I hope so.
因为我不想亲自来找你，听到了吗？
'Cause I don't want to have to come looking for you. You hear me?
- 我们走，布洛 - 我都差点尿裤了
- Come on, Bruno. - I just shit in my pants, right?
那是老板，唐尼
It's the boss, Donnie.
好，乔，局子里要你签字
Okay, Joe, the Bureau wants your autograph.
- 你要我签什么？ - 得了吧
- What's that, you want me to sign it? - Forget about it.
这样就对了
"Forget about it" is right.
听着，他们要你刮掉胡须，那是规矩
Listen, by the way, they want you to shave the mustache. Regulations.
他们怎么知道我有胡须？
How did they even know about the mustache?
- 你告发的我？  - 我没有
- Did you rat me out? - I didn't rat you out.
- 你给他们看的  - 哦，不错
- Show and tell. - Yeah. Nice.
- 什么？ - 他也要我去刮掉它
- What? - So does he. He wants me to shave.
- 谁？左撇子鲁吉洛？ - 是的
- Who? Ruggiero? - Yeah.
是行规
Regulations. Here.
你知道吗？
You know something?
我骗过他了，他已经上钩了
I got him. I got my hooks in the guy.
被非洲草原上的草遮挡着
Cloaked by the high grasses of the African Savannah,
猎豹躲在草丛里慢慢靠近它的猎物
the stalking cheetah moves stealthily towards his prey.
- 你好  - 你来找我爸的？
- How you doing? - You're here for my dad?
是的，我是唐尼
Yeah. I'm Donnie.
- 汤米，你好吗？  - 好
- Tommy. How are you? - Good.
- 圣诞快乐，进来吧  - 谢谢
- Merry Christmas. Come on in. - Thanks.
- 贝尼在看电视，你遇到托米了？  - 是的，谢谢
- Benny's watching TV. You met Tommy? - Yes, we met. Thank you.
落单的小羚羊感到了危险
Separated from the herd, the gazelle senses danger.
本尼，唐尼来了
Benny, Donnie's here.
太迟了，猎豹冲刺了
Too late. The cheetah springs.
贝尼喜欢动物
Benny loves animals.
- 看到了吗？  - 我去厨房，有事叫我
- You see that? - I'll be in the kitchen if you need me.
- 猎杀与被猎杀…  - 你看那儿
- Hunter and hunted. - Look at that.
掠食者与猎物之前，残酷的自然法则
Predator and prey. The endless cycle of nature repeated.
给你这个，一个小小的圣诞礼物
I brought this by for you. It's a little Christmas present.
噢，好，等等
Yeah, wait a minute. Here.
请原谅，老左，我来得不是时候
I'm sorry, Left, but I'm in a little bit of a rush here, you know? So...
- 圣诞快乐！  - 谢谢
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you.
你真好
That's really nice of you.
噢，你瞧！
Wow. Look at this.
你真慷慨，唐尼，孩子
Very generous of you, Donnie. Thank you. Good boy.
- 好了，节日快乐 - 你去哪儿？
- All right. So, happy holidays. - Where you going?
- 你不是孤儿吗？  - 是啊
- I thought you was an orphan. - Yeah.
- 你想去哪儿？  - 我不想打扰你
- So what are you gonna do? - Left, I don't want to spoil your day.
过来，过来
Come on.
我的人都不能独自过圣诞
No man of mine is gonna be alone on Christmas. Come on in here.
到这儿来
Come on.
你怕我做的东西不好吃吗？
You think I cook like them goombahs in Brooklyn?
有些人就知道通心粉 一百年后，还是通心粉
All they know is manicotti. A hundred years, they'll be eating manicotti.
- 你不喜欢酒焖子鸡吗？  - 不
- You never ate coq au vin? - No.
好嘞
There we are.
蛋白胶，蕃茄
Can of collagen, can of tomatoes.
- 来一把盐  - “一把”？
- Punch of salt. - "Punch"?
- 一把盐？  - 一把还是一撮？
- Punch. Punch of salt? - "Punch" or "pinch"?
一把，不是一撮
"Punch," not "pinch."
- 我说过一撮吗？ - 不，你说的是“一把”
- Did I say "pinch"? - No, you said "punch."
唐尼，有时你真他妈会胡说八道
Sometimes you don't make no fucking sense, Donnie.
- 都是你做的，安妮特？  - 我可没贝尼那样的好厨艺
- You got all this, Annette? - I can't cook special like Benny.
好了，安妮特，别提了
Shut up, Annette. Forget about it.
不管在哪儿，最好的厨师都是男人
Wherever you go, the best cooks are men.
火星上也一样，真的
On Mars, the best cooks are gonna be men. That's a fact.
等着品我的酒焖子鸡吧
Wait till you taste this coq au vin.
一到嘴里就像圣餐一样化了
It's gonna melt in your mouth, like Holy Communion.
噢，这是干嘛，安妮特，盖上
What the fuck is that? Annette, get that.
- 谢谢  - 没啥
- Thank you. - Sure.
- 谢谢你，安妮特  - 没啥，本尼
- Thanks, Annette. - Sure, Benny.
她真是个好女人
She's a good woman, Annette.
心眼好，能容得下任何人
One broad, that's enough for anyone.
老爸，我要出去一会儿，好吗
Pop, I'm going out for a couple of hours, okay?
圣诞快乐，唐尼，再见
Merry Christmas. Donnie, take care.
圣诞快乐，玩得开心点
Yeah, you, too. Take it easy.
这混小子又来瘾了，你能相信吗？
My own fucking son's a junkie. Can you believe it?
你能怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
把他嘴巴堵上吗？
Give him a smack in the mouth once in a while.
我的手不行了
I got bruises on my hands.
你不知我有多担心，唐尼
You don't know the worries I got, Donnie.
安妮特这种女人，我对不住她 我身上一块钱都拿不出
A woman like Annette, I can't do right by her. I ain't got $3 in my pocket.
我去赌马，结果连马也在那里偷懒
I put a bet on a horse, that horse don't do what it's supposed to do,
我的生活就是这样，我老二长了瘤
like every fucking thing else in my life. I got cancer of the prick.
知道吗？我前妻住在一幢大楼里
My ex-wife lives in this building.
有次在电梯里碰到她
Can you believe it? I run into her in the elevator.
我喝了三杯汽酒才平静下来
I got to have three spritzers afterward just to calm down after I see her.
你刚才说什么？什么长瘤？
What are you talking about, cancer of the prick?
老二长了瘤，听不懂吗？
It's cancer of the prick. You didn't know that?
我看医学书上看来的
I'm in the medical books for that.
我过去有一艘50尺长的伯伦特游船
I got this boat, too, this Bertram. 50-foot Bertram with twin Chryslers.
向红桑还钱，我把它出手了
I had to get rid of it for money I owe Sonny Red.
一周光利息就要3千
The vig alone is $3,000 a week.
- 旁边那人是谁？  - 布诺，他的儿子
- Who's that guy with him? - Bruno? That's his son.
- 我想让他脑袋开花  - 不行，你别这样，唐尼
- I'd like to put a dent in that guy's head. - No, you don't do that, Donnie.
- 你别动他  - 我知道，我是说我想
- You don't touch him. - I know. I'm saying I wish I could.
你想？
You wish?
那人可不是你这样的人惹得起的
A guy like you doesn't touch a made guy.
你知道我昨天怎么样吗？
You know what I did yesterday?
我当着他的所有心腹以及红桑尼，他们全部
I went in front of all the skippers. That cocksucker Sonny Red, all of them.
我想让人记得你，明白我意思吗？
I went on the record with you. You know what that means?
我想是吧
I think I do.
你明白？你明白个屁
You do? You ain't got no fucking idea, my friend.
现在没人敢碰你，你是我的人
Nobody can touch you now. I'm your man.
耶稣基督也不能碰你，因为我罩着你
Jesus Christ couldn't touch you, because I represent you.
那么保持手脚干净，做一个会挣钱的人
So keep your nose clean, be a good earner,
遵守规则，然后谁知道呢
follow the rules, and who knows,
哪天要是有机会，你就扶摇直上了
maybe one day when they open the books, you get straightened out.
成为一个大哥
Become a wise guy.
一个老大级的人物，来举杯
A made guy. Come on, lift your glass.
为我们生死与共，我会罩着你的
I'd die with you, Donnie. Anything happens, I'm responsible.
- 好吗？  - 好吗？
- All right? - All right.
- 干杯  - 干杯
- Salute. - Salute.
行了，别送了
All right, Don.
- 多谢了，你太好了  - 能否为我俩的友谊表示一下？借我个一百块钱？
- Thanks a lot. It was excellent. - Could you spot me a couple hundred?
- 好  - 我会还你的，放心
- Yeah, okay. - I'll get it back to you. You got it here.
拿去吧
Here you go.
- 我会在这里还你  - 好的
- I'll get back to you on this. - Yeah.
- 相信我，明天给我电话  - 好
- Believe me. Call me tomorrow. - All right.
喂
Hello.
- 你总算回来了  - 圣诞快乐
- Look what the reindeer dragged in. - Merry Christmas.
我上班去了，我也没办法
I was working. Nothing I could do.
上班？
Working?
- 乔，谁会要圣诞节上班？  - 我要
- Who works Christmas Day, Joe? - I do.
- 孩子们在哪儿？  - 他们等不了了
- Where's the kids? - They couldn't wait anymore.
有意思
Well, that's nice.
圣诞节都不等老爸回来
Christmas, they can't wait up for their father.
- 这样就算是道歉了吗？ - 你知道我很抱歉
- Is that your way of saying you're sorry? - You know I'm sorry.
我无所谓，可是你得让女儿们知道
I don't need to know. The girls need to know.
别忘了到时候先介绍自己
Only be sure to introduce yourself.
免得她们把你认成推销员
They might think you're the Fuller brush man.
- 你要是知道我今天在做什么的话  - 我不知道
- If you knew what I was doing today... - I don't have an idea
- 因为你不告诉我，不是吗？  - 那是为了保护你
- because you don't tell me, remember? - Because it's for your own protection.
总是说的是为了我一样
As if any of this is for me.
支票收到了吗？
You're getting the checks, right?
- 是的，收到了  - 那就别把我说得一无是处
- I'm getting the checks. - Good. Then don't say it like it's nothing.
- 不是一无是处  - 对，不是也不是个好丈夫
- 'Cause it's not nothing. - It's not nothing, but it's not a husband.
多数女性不会这么想的
A lot of women would disagree with you.
你在外面就是干这个？
Is that what you do with all your time?
- 让你的女人们填调查问卷？  - 我不想把自己说得有多好
- Conduct polls with all your women? - I'm not even gonna dignify that.
我每天在外亡命，回家你就这样
Seven days a week, I'm out there busting my ass, and this is the shit I come home to.
以前说再要三个月，可这已经两年了
You said it was gonna be three months. It's going on two years.
你把麦片弄得到处都是，还怎么找？
How do you find anything in here? You got cereal on three shelves.
到处乱扔
You got cereals over here.
原谅我一次吧，这是因为工作呀
Put stuff away for once. It's my job.
- 辞职？  - 那我的工作怎么办？
- Quit my job? - What about my job, Joe?
圣诞节你不在，圣诞老人都是我妈妈扮的
Christmas Day you don't show up, so Mommy puts on the Santa suit.
是我妈妈挂的灯，切的肉
Mommy hangs the lights. Mommy carves the roast.
- 别说了  - 乔瑟夫
- You just leave it alone. - Joseph.
- 你要是告诉我真相，我会好受点  - 饶了我吧
- It would be easier if you tell me... - Just give me a break.
你究竟在做什么？
...what goes on with these guys, what you do.
别说了，拜托，让我安静会
Just shut up, please. Leave me alone.
泰莉和凯莉在我妈妈那里，干嘛不去接她们？
Terry and Kerry are at my mother's. Why don't you go pick them up?
谢莉在哪儿？
Where's Sherry?
谢莉在男朋友家
Sherry is with her boyfriend.
- 什么？  - 她在男朋友家里
- What? - She's at her boyfriend's.
- 什么时候谢莉都有男朋友了？  - 她已经十二岁了，乔
- Since when does she have a boyfriend? - She's 12, Joe.
- 玛姬，这样可不行  - 不行？你想怎么办？
- I didn't okay this, Maggie. - Okay it? What do you think?
你就突然上帝一样的出现然后发号施令？
You can drop out of the sky like God and bark orders?
我是丈夫，父亲，我养家糊口！
I am the husband and the father! I put food on that table!
- 秘密的丈夫  - 我都不曾过过圣诞节
- Undercover husband! - What do I get for Christmas?
该死的一无所有的房子
Empty fucking house!
我在这里
I'm here.
我想陪在你身边
I wanted to be alone with you.
噢！天哪！
Oh, God.
你胡子怎么没了？
What happened to your 'stache?
局子里要我刮的，你能相信吗？
The B, they made me shave it off. Can you believe that?
- 不是吧？  - 是真的
- They didn't. - Yeah.
这是你工作唯一的可取之处了
It was the only thing I liked about this job.
- 谢莉真的有男朋友了？  - 是的，她有了
- So, Sherry got a boyfriend? - Yeah, she does.
那男孩不错，真的
Nice kid. He's so nice.
他是摔角队的
He's on the wrestling team.
噢，我相信他是摔角队的
I'll bet he's on the wrestling team.
凯莉在做教义问答，很听话
Kerry's doing the catechism. So sweet.
他们在学游泳
And they're swimming.
教练说他从没见过这么好的孩子
Coach says he's never seen nothing like it.
星期六有个聚会
There's a meet Saturday.
要我怎么样？再说吧
What am I gonna do? We'll see.
我把事情都交给你是因为我信任你
You know that I wouldn't do this to you if I didn't think you could handle it.
我不是在担心我自己，乔
I'm not worried about me, Joe.
好了，宝贝们，怎么了？
All right, what's going on, kids?
你们都不理我了？
Am I getting the silent treatment?
我们来打个赌
I'll make a bet with you.
我出二十元赌…
I'll bet you $20
赌你们吃完饭之前至少要说三个字
that you can't get through this entire meal without saying three words.
好吗？
All right?
你输
You lose.
她说什么？
What did she say?
她说的什么？
姑娘们，过来一会，到这里来，特瑞，谢莉
Girls, come here a second. Come here, Terry, Kerry.
过来，对不起，甜心过来，我们去看你姐姐
Come on. Sorry, sweetie. Come on. Let's go see your sister.
上楼去
Come on upstairs.
看一会书
Let's just, let's read a book.
听话
Do what you're told.
老左，我是唐尼，我来报道了
Left, it's Donnie. I'm checking in.
是的，我说我来报道了
Yeah, that's what I said. I'm checking in.
不，我整天都在外面，发生什么了？
No. I've been out all day. What's going on?
好，再见
All right. So long.
你没看报吗？你居然没有看报？
You didn't see the paper? How come you didn't see the paper?
你每天早上要看报，那今天早上都读了什么？
Every morning you're reading the paper. What were you reading this morning?
看看这个
Look at this.
你能相信吗？老板被人做了
Can you believe this? The boss gets whacked. The fucking boss.
也只有他被人做的消息我能知道
You never hear from the boss until he gets whacked
- 然后你的生活却被改变了  - 我们要去哪？
- and then your life gets turned around. - Want to tell me where we're going?
- 我被请去干活  - 那是什么意思？
- I got sent for. - So what does that mean?
- 我被请去干活  - 那是什么意思呢？
- You got sent for. - What does that mean?
你以为是什么意思？
What do you think it means?
你不想去？你要我回去？那我就回去
You don't wanna go? You want me to turn around? I'll turn around.
你想干什么？在桥上掉头吗？
What are you gonna do? Take a left off the fucking bridge?
- 不是这里，过了桥那边  - 不，我也要去
- Not here, I'm saying after the bridge. - No, I gotta go.
你要是被请了，你也去，桑尼只请了我
You get sent for, you go. Sonny sent for me.
我真是受够了
I'm sick of this.
- 红桑请你去吗？ - 我说是红桑吗？
- You got sent for by Sonny Red? - Did I say Sonny Red?
不是红桑是黑桑
Not Sonny Red. Sonny Black.
唐尼，你想干什么？关上…
Donnie, what are you doing? Put the fuck...
你想用那冷风冻死我吗？
Donnie, you wanna kill me with that draft?
黑桑不是你朋友么？有什么不可以吗？
Left, Sonny Black is your friend. What's the big deal?
对，我们比较熟，但绝对算不上朋友
Right. We're friendly. Ain't the question, "friend."
黑桑在监狱的时候
The whole time Sonny Black's in the can, the whole time...
他已成家，可他还有一个情妇
He's got a family, he's got a mistress.
还有情妇的情妇
He's got a mistress for the mistress.
他们都是我照顾的，只有我
I watched out for them, all of them. Me, I was the only one.
别人谁都不给一个子儿
Nobody else gave a fuck.
每周给两百块，一周接一周的给
Two hundred fazools, week in, week out.
你很会为黑桑着想，那你有什么可担心的呢？
So you took care of Sonny Black. What are you worried about, then?
有时候我会想 是不是你在孤儿院时把脑袋摔坏了
Sometimes I think, in that orphanage, they dropped you on your fucking head.
你不解释我怎么知道？
How am I supposed to know if you don't explain it?
但我知道那里头的滋味
You think I don't know how a hit gets set up?
你以为我不知道吗？
You think I don't know that?
我都知道
You know, what I know.
知道我进去过多少次吗？
How many times have I been on the other end of that fucking phone?
- 二十六次  - 厉害
- Twenty-six times. - Great.
你这不就在说黑桑和你是朋友
You just got done saying you and Sonny Black are friends.
唐尼，人家请我了
Donnie, I got sent for.
我们这行，被人要了 就是替人卖命，替人吃枪子
In our thing, you get sent for, you go in alive, you come out dead
而且常常就是你最好的朋友开的枪
and it's your best friend that does it.
我现在不安全 若出什么事一定要把车留给安妮特
Anything should happen to me, make sure Annette gets the car.
- 喝一杯，老左？  - 晚点吧
- Spritzer, Left? - Later, maybe.
你瞧那手，根本就不像是手
Look at this hand. This ain't a hand.
长得就像我见过的那种湖怪一样
This is a fucking deformed Creature from the Black Lagoon's claw I got here.
嘿，老左
Hey, Left.
- 你把那些都押了？  - 我不知道
- You throwing that down? - I don't know.
赢了
Gin.
好运突然爆发是不奇怪的
Love on the rocks ain't no surprise
- 鲍利，那不是炸  - 那也不奇怪
- Paulie, that ain't gin. - Ain't no fucking surprise, neither.
赢了
It's gin.
你说什么？你有对7
What are you talking? You got two sevens.
我是三条7
I had three sevens.
- 鲍利  - 尼克，我有三张7
- Paulie. - Nicky, I had three sevens.
我知道我有三张7，别瞎搞
I know I had three sevens. Don't start this shit now.
你知道你有三张7？你没有三张7
You know you had three sevens? You don't have three sevens.
我有三张7
I had three sevens.
从现在起，我洗牌，随你怎么说
From now on, I'll deal out the cards, you say "gin" whenever you feel like it.
妈的，押了200，拿回来多少？5块？
Fucking booths. $200 in action and what we have we got, five?
这周手风又不顺，桑尼
We're taking a beating again this week, Sonny.
上车再说吧，我有辆新车
Let's go for a ride. I got a new car.
开这车去兜风无比拉风啊
Can you believe the ride on this car?
我真不明白那些德国人怎么输掉了战争
I can't understand how they lost a war, them Germans.
- 我今晚在泽西有个约会  - 和哪个小妞？
- I got a date out in Jersey tonight. - Which broad is this?
日历上那个，彭素利小姐
The one from the calendar. Miss Pennzoil Air Filter of 1978.
- 他干什么？往镜子里看什么？  - 你干吗，老左？
- What's he doing looking in the mirror? - What're you doing over there, Left?
觉得我是在干吗？
What's it look like I'm doing?
我看我的唇膏
I'm checking my lipstick.
没有你我们要怎么办？老左？
What would I do without you, Left? What would I do?
你呢，唐尼？你会怎么办？
What about you, Donnie? What would you do?
给自己另找个老大，是不是？
Have to find yourself a new goombah, wouldn't you?
我们老板出了点事
That was something about the boss, huh?
出来混都要还的
We all gotta go sometime.
我们在这里干什么，桑尼？ 我们是来偷东西吗？
What are we doing here, Sonny? We glomming something, or what?
- 不  - 你在车里等着
- No. - You, wait in the car.
- 什么？  - 看着车
- What? - Watch the car.
噢，妈的！
Oh, fuck!
该死！
Shit!
上帝啊，我差点尿裤子，这是什么？
Christ, I think I shit my pants. What is this?
它应该去驯兽师那里
He's supposed to go to an animal trainer somewhere.
- 去它的  - 老左，我觉得它喜欢你
- Fuck him. - Left, I think he likes you.
- 或者它是饿了 - 它跟我有什么关系？
- Either that or he's just hungry. - What's he got to do with me?
- 桑尼，干什么用的？  - 给你的
- Sonny, what is this? - It's for you.
给我的？
For me?
我知道你喜欢动物
I know how you feel about animals.
这是给你的礼物
It's a gift from me.
- 给我的？  - 是的
- It's for me? - Yeah.
现在我说了算，你要听我的
I got the power. Now you're under me.
- 你什么意思？什么你说了算？  - 桑尼提升了
- What do you mean, you got the power? - Sonny got upped.
什么？你提升了吗？
What, you got upped?
是鲁斯提在狱中安排的
Rusty's gonna run the whole thing from the can.
小意大利归红桑，布鲁克林归我
Sonny Red's got Little Italy. I got Brooklyn.
那你请我来干什么？
That's why you sent for me?
是啊，你说呢？你以为我们要干掉你？
Yeah, why? What did you think, you was gonna get whacked?
左兄以为他要被干掉了
Lefty thought he was gonna get whacked.
恭喜了，过来
Congratulations. Come here.
真不错
Good stuff.
带上你的猫咪，我们走
Grab the pussy. Let's go.
这个我要怎么养？
What am I gonna do with this?
他认为它们会很臭
He thinks they smell fear.
真麻烦
I'm sick of this.
你和黑桑是朋友
You and Sonny Black are friends.
我说过了，别提黑桑
I got told to shut my mouth about Sonny Black.
为了他有多少次我勇敢的反对老板，那个混蛋
How many times I stood up to the boss himself, that cocksucker.
愿他安息
May he rest in peace.
你必须要…你必须要…
You're gonna have to... You're gonna have to...
我去…
I got...
我要40个汉堡
I'm gonna need 40 of those burgers.
不要洋葱
Hold the onions.
黑桑混上去了，我也不傻
Sonny Black, they make skipper. I ain't a mutt.
三十年辛辛苦苦，得到什么？
Thirty years busting my hump. For what?
一头狮子，就是你
A lion.
五个小时前，你还觉得可能会被干掉
Five hours ago, you thought you was gonna get whacked.
- 嘿，唐尼，我说过我要被干掉了吗？ - 没说这么细…
- Donnie, did I say I was gonna get whacked? - Not in so many words.
我不懂，我到底说的多细了？
I don't understand you. How many words does it take?
你是对的，是我误会了
You're right. I misunderstood.
辛苦了三十年，大小事都叫我出面
Thirty years I'm earning. Any work to be done, call Lefty.
我从没抱怨过，少说也干掉了26个家伙
I never complained. Twenty-six guys I clipped.
提升过我吗？从没轮到我
Do I get upped? No, they pass me by.
黑桑高升了，而我却没有
Sonny Black gets upped. I don't get fucking upped.
做掉老板这件事桑尼可能也有份
Sonny was probably in on whacking the boss.
当然有份
Of course he was in on whacking the boss.
除掉老板，这也瞒着我
Whacking the boss. Another thing I get left out of.
这些人，你知道，很官僚
It's like one of those, whatchamacallit, you know, bureaucracy.
什么官僚？不是官僚，你在说什么？官僚？
What bureaucracy? Ain't no bureaucracy. What you talking about, bureaucracy?
你怎么想出来的？官僚论？
Where the fuck do you get your ideas? Bureaucracy.
我意思是，我在说他们不懂欣赏你
All I'm saying, I'm saying they don't appreciate you, is what I'm saying.
欣赏？那他们欣赏你？
Appreciate? They appreciate you?
- 干嘛，老左，我是你这边的  - 你站在我这边？
- Come on, Left, I'm on your side. - You're on my side?
我说你是我这边的，你就是我这边的
You're on my side because I say you're on my side.
嘿，听着，唐尼！
Hey, look. Donnie!
不要自以为是，唐尼
Don't get on your fucking high horse, Donnie.
我不喜欢那样
I don't like that.
但是，告诉你
But tell you what.
看那个
Look at that.
我想再搞条伯伦特型的船
I wish I had that boat again, that Bertram.
我希望我拥有条船
I wish I had that boat.
我带上安妮特开这车，开到码头
I'd get in my car with Annette, I'd drive down to the pier
想去哪儿就去哪儿
I'd get on that boat and I'd go.
我要离开
I'd go.
天涯海角，没人能找到我
East, west, north, south, nobody'd ever find me.
你看现在，真他妈丢人
Look at this thing. It's a fucking insult.
走吧，快！快！
Let's go! Come on.
我把这个给他！
I gave it to him!
- 不！桑尼，算了！ - 天呐！
- Come on, Sonny! - Jesus!
- 不，桑尼！不  - 他拿到钱了
- No, Sonny! Please. - He's got the money.
- 他是我的朋友  - 光天化日下，我简直不能相信
- He was a friend of mine. - Broad daylight. I can't believe it.
谁能光天化日下在街上拿走别人的东西
What kind of people are gonna take another man's property right off the street?
算了吧
Forget about it.
整个社会都堕落到地铁里了
The whole society's going down the tubes.
尼克松在任的时候我们从来没有这种问题
We never had this kind of a problem when Nixon was around.
尼克松？尼克松？尼克松得了吧，尼克松
Nixon? Nixon? Forget about Nixon. Nixon.
全世界都尊重我们
We had respect all over the world.
我们有权利
We stood for something.
在街区里我们说了算
We had law and order in the street.
我们有过一些不同的故事
We had a little different story.
真可惜他不是西西里人
Too bad he wasn't Sicilian.
他是西西里人
He was Sicilian.
你知道，昨晚我看见罗杰·格雷上新闻了
You know, last night I'm watching Roger Grimsby on the news
那些穆斯林小丑们又在街上游行
and those Ayatollah cockamamie people are marching through the streets,
他们相互鞭打背脊
and they're whipping each other on the back with whips.
胡说八道，我从没听说过
Get out of here. I never heard of that.
- 唐尼，我还好吗？  - 什么？
- Donnie, am I right? - What?
他妈的狂想家
Fucking fanatics over there.
你为什么问他？
What're you asking him for? What're you asking him for?
这算什么，唱双簧？我在问他问题
What was it, a ventriloquist act? I asked him a question...
但和我说干嘛，你问他去
But you're talking to me. You're asking him.
他读…你什么意思，为什么我问他？
He reads... What do you mean, why am I asking him?
去他妈的读报，你问我，你在问他什么？
Fuck if he reads. You ask me. What're you asking him?
- 你看报了？  - 我在这里，在和你说话
- Did you see it? - I'm here. You're talking to me.
你在和我说话，那你和他说话干嘛？
You're talking to me. What are you talking to him for?
我先和你说，然后我和他说 我和每个人都说
I talk to you, then I talk to him. I talk to everybody.
好吧，好吧
All right, all right, all right.
桑尼，过来，波比
Sonny, come here. Bobby.
见到你真高兴
Good seeing you.
波比，给桑尼找个好座 开一瓶最好的酒，我买单
Bobby, give Sonny a good table and a bottle of your best, on me.
你该给他配个裁缝才是
Why don't you get him a tailor while you're at it?
- 你好吗？克特  - 最近怎么样？
- What do you say, Curley? - How's it going?
这是华盛顿来的迪恩·布兰福
This is Dean Blanford, he's from Washington.
- 乔  - 唐尼
- Joe. - Donnie.
叫我唐尼吧，我不想惹麻烦
Call me Donnie. I don't want to get confused.
我懂，伙计，只是有时候一忙就忘了
I know what you mean, pal. Sometimes you get so busy,
- 有时候连自己名字都忘了  - 噢，是吗？
- even I forget my own name. - Yeah, is that right?
那岂不是不能用支票了？
Is it hard to cash checks?
迪恩是华盛顿来的
Dean's up from Washington.
对，你已经说过了，然后呢？
Yeah, you said that part already. What's next?
现在行动已经产生效果了
Now that the operation is beginning to bear fruit
总部决定调我到…这罪恶的城市
headquarters decided to transfer me up to Sin City here.
- 干什么？派你来监视我吗？  - 不
- What for? You want to keep an eye on me? - No.
来保证你应有的后援
To make sure you receive the proper support.
- 应有的后援？ - 还要确保在一片混乱的时候
- The proper support. - And to make sure, in all the hubbub,
- 你没有错失良机  - 错失良机？比如呢？
- there are no missed opportunities. - Missed opportunities? Like what?
迈阿密的探员里奇·卡佐也在着手
We have an agent in Miami, goes by the name of Richie Gazzo.
- 迈阿密？  - 现在他那边可能比较好办
- Miami? - His operation is potentially very sweet.
问题是需要提早行动
Problem is, it's starting to languish right now and needs jump-starting.
现在局里要你深入进去
The Bureau would like you to go down there
看是否能尽快取得信任
and see if you could interest some of your mob friends.
- 假如你替里奇担保…  - 我不会替我不认识的人担保
- If you vouch for Richie Gazzo... - I ain't vouching for nobody I don't know.
我还指望我们能谈得来
I was hoping we'd get off on the right foot here.
瞧，有什么大不了的？ 你只要深入进去并替他担保
What's the big deal? You just go down and vouch for the guy.
让他先露面
Sit in the sun for a week.
- 我担保他，我可能会没命的  - 他可能也会
- If I vouch for the guy, I could wind up dead. - So could he.
你不是唯一一个冒生命危险的人
You're not the only one out there risking your life, bud.
我再考虑考虑
I'll let you know.
再联系
I'll get back to you.
他会让我们知道吗？
He'll let us know?
- 晚上好，几位？  - 五位
- Good evening. How many? - Five.
我老婆说日本菜很流行 她从普拉达杂志上看到的
My wife says it's very in, Japanese. She read about it in Parade magazine.
非常有名
Very big now.
请坐，请脱鞋
Have seat. Take off shoes. Please.
- 这是什么东西？  - 海鲜什么的
- What kind of food is this? - It's fish.
- 请脱鞋  - 开玩笑吗？
- Please, take off shoes. - Are you kidding me?
那你把裤子脱了，这算什么嘛？
Take off your pants. What's that?
这是规定
I'm afraid it's necessary.
- 这是日本人的习俗  - 是吗？
- It's Japanese tradition. - Is that right?
- 得了吧，我就不脱  - 这恐怕不行
- Forget about it, I ain't doing it. - I'm afraid it's necessary.
我他妈就不脱
Forget it, I ain't taking my fucking shoes off.
- 喂，唐尼  - 怎么？
- Hey, Donnie. - What?
在罗马…
When in Rome...
尼克，谁赢了那场战争
Nicky, who won the fucking war?
- 战争？什么战争？  - 我们赢的那场，你想再打一仗吗？
- War? What war? - We did. Do you want to fight it again?
- 脱下你的鞋  - 我就不脱
- Take off your shoes. - I ain't gonna do it.
- 脱了吧  - 就不
- Take your shoes off. - I ain't taking my shoes off.
我今晚是来吃东西的
I want to eat sometime tonight.
要么脱了要么把他妈的脚砍下来
Take off your shoes, or I'm gonna chop off your fucking feet.
桑尼，你要我干什么？
What do you want me to do?
你要我听从该死的日本人？
You want me to take orders from a fucking Jap?
就因为我家人在冲绳被日本人杀害 我才从小在孤儿院长大
I grew up in an orphanage because my old man was killed in Okinawa.
你说我该不该听这个王八的话？
You think I'm taking my shoes off for this fucking prick?
不，我绝不
No, I ain't doing it.
恐怕你必须脱
I'm afraid it's necessary.
听着，我这朋友是不会脱他的鞋子的 杉本先生
Listen, my friend's not gonna take off his shoes there, Mr. Moto.
这恐怕不行
I'm afraid it's necessary.
而且我们也不脱了 趁我没揍你，请带我们入座
Neither are the rest of us. So give us a table before I smack you.
你必须把鞋脱了
You must take off your shoes.
- 你喜欢鞋？你他妈的！ - 按住他！
- You like shoes, you fuck? - Get him down!
喜欢吗？
You like shoes?
让我来！
Let me get in there.
你这个王八蛋！
Slant-eyed motherfucker!
- 好了，我们走  - 你这杂种！
- Come on. Let's go. - Son of a bitch!
- 揍他！唐尼！ - 笨猪！
- Watch him, Donnie! - Stupid fuck!
唐尼，揍得他满地找牙，揍死他！
Kick the shit out of him, Donnie! Kick him!
用这个，用靴子！
Use those fucking boots!
别动，你他妈的别动！
Don't you move, you fuck. Don't you fucking move.
你他妈的喜欢鞋？
You like shoes, you fuck?
王八蛋！
Slant-eyed motherfucker!
- 好了，我们走吧  - 狗娘养的！
- Come on. Let's go. - Son of a bitch!
小心！唐尼！
Watch him, Donnie!
笨猪！
Stupid fuck!
揍他！揍死他！唐尼
Kick the shit out of him, Donnie! Kick him!
多管闲事
Mind your own business.
回家去！回去吧！
Just go home! Go home!
回家去，你这贱货
Go home, you miserable bitch.
你在做什么？桑尼准备开工了
What you doing? Sonny's ready to start.
他还没开始，你想要他把尿撒在地板上？
He's not done yet. You want him to piss all over the fucking floor?
雪茄，他们卖50元一盒
...not sharing the cigars. Up the block, they sell for $50 a box.
我们可以卖25元
We could sell them for $25.
你先给你马子弄两、三盒 让她干啥她就会干啥
You give two or three of those to a broad, she'll do anything you want.
那我给老婆点，她岂不是会做饭了
Give three Quaaludes to Brenda. Maybe she'd cook.
这个比较难
I doubt it.
我在圣迭戈瓦伦特找到一个家伙
I got a guy that's in the middle of this load of Sergio Valentes.
可以弄到非常低的利息
A dime on the vig.
- 你这月收了多少保护费？  - 10万
- So, what do you got on the street? - $100,000.
到年底应该有25万美元
That should be $250,000 by the end of the year.
我能以低价拿到这些货，我能找人来运
I can get these real cheap and I got a guy who can move them.
你他妈别敲了行不？
Will you fucking stop that?
那我还能怎么弄？
How else am I supposed to open this?
芝麻开门！
Open sesame!
事实上
A score's a score.
你看这个，有一百对
Boss, look what I got here. It's 100 pairs.
红桑在泽西赚了一百万
Sonny Red's got $1 million a month with his trucks in Jersey.
我们能干什么？去停车场收费？
What do I get? Steak knives and parking meters.
应该去抢辆油车，现在油值钱
We ought to hijack an oil tanker. There's a lot of money in oil.
喂，你知道吗？
You know something?
我有个佛罗里达的朋友，他说那里很有市场
There's a guy I know down in Florida. He says it's wide open down there.
- 在佛罗里达的哪里？ - 佛罗里达的海边
- Where in Florida? - Florida. The beach.
那带的经济在下滑
The whole economy's moving down there. They call it the Sun Belt.
经济不好，我们就赚不到大钱？
The economy's got to be good for us to make any real money.
你以为在佛罗里达没人干这行？
You don't think they got their own wise guys in Florida?
佛罗里达和亚利桑那，因为能源危机
Florida and Arizona because of the energy crisis.
我在一档电视节目里听说的
I heard a whole conversation on the Long John Neville Show.
而在这里，数千人去追逐那些蝇头小利
Problem up here, you got 3,000 wise guys all chasing the same fucking nickel.
你是从佛罗里达来的吧？唐尼
You're from down there, Florida, Donnie?
那里倒是有很多停车场
Lot of parking meters down in Florida.
你们觉得这样有趣？
You guys think this is funny?
现在是我当家，我得给上面交代！
I'm the skipper now. I gotta answer!
每月要给鲁斯提五万块，我受够了
$50,000 a month, I kick up to Rusty. Every month!
哪天我会被气死的！
One day, I'm gonna die.
我要死在这间房子里，和你们一起！
I'm gonna be here in this same room with all these same fucking guys
跟你们这帮混蛋一起
talking about the same fucking scams
整天就知道废话连篇
that never amount to nothing!
和你们在一起就像是在地狱一样
That's how I'll know that I've been sent to fucking hell.
乔，再给这些混混喝一点 他们反正也就好这口
Joe, give these humps another drink. It's all they're good for.
谁要是不想被赶走，就想办法赚钱吧
I tell you right now, we better start earning or somebody's gonna get clipped.
唐尼，你干嘛会提起去佛州呢？
Why did you inject that, Donnie, with Florida?
你在说什么？我什么都没提
What are you talking about? I didn't inject nothing.
是你提出的，别跟我说没有
You injected that. Don't tell me no.
我了解你，你说话都是有目的的
I know you. You don't say nothing unless there's a reason for it.
现在，这个佛罗里达的家伙是谁？
Now, who is this fucking guy in Florida?
谁也不是 只是一个我住在那里的时候认识的人
Nobody. He's a guy I knew when I lived down there, that's all.
你担保这个人吗？
You vouch for this guy?
嘿，算了吧，我只是随便说说
Hey, come on. That was bullshitting around.
随便说说？你认为黑桑只是说废话？
Bullshitting around? What, you think Sonny Black is just bullshitting around?
我知道什么？我不知道，你说你知道他不是？
What do I know? I don't... You know... You think he wasn't?
好了，听我说，唐尼 我都不知道我要对谁发誓
Yeah, well... Listen to me, Donnie, I don't know what to swear on.
对我死去的父亲，我爱的妈妈 还是我的孩子
My dead father, my mother who I love, my children.
我向你发誓，唐尼，有些事是你不知道的
I swear to you, Donnie, something is going on you don't know about.
- 我和他说了点话  - 能说会道的家伙
- I was making conversation with the guy. - Mr. Smart Conversation,
告诉我你们说了些什么
you tell me what happens
如果黑桑决定去佛州
if Sonny Black decides he wants to go to Florida?
谁说他去了佛州？
Who said he's going to go to Florida?
唐尼，你别以为你能瞒得了我
Donnie, don't think you can pull the wool over my eyes.
我知道你在讨好桑尼
I see you siding up to Sonny Black.
我亲眼看见你这样做了
With my eyes, I'm looking at you. You're doing it.
- 得了吧  - 我没有讨好桑尼
- Come on. - I ain't siding up to Sonny Black.
他要去了佛州，出什么事你得负责
He goes to Florida, you're responsible.
我也要负责，因为我要代表你
And I'm responsible because I represent you.
老左，好了，我只是随便说说
Come on. I was just bullshitting around.
你以为能相信黑桑，你不能相信他
You think you can trust Sonny Black. You can't trust Sonny Black.
黑桑是条又长又肥的蛇…
Sonny Black is one big, fat, fucking snake in the...
- 草原，草原上的蛇  - 现在还不能这样说
- Grass. Snake in the grass. - You can't say that now.
现在是他当家，别乱讲他
Sonny Black is a skipper. You don't open your mouth about him.
老左，是里奇的电话，他说
Lefty, this fucking guy Richie calls me up. He says,
他正在和一群麻烦的家伙谈条件
"I'm getting hassled by a couple of half-assed wise guys."
他被那些家伙烦得不行了 所以想找人跟他合伙
He's looking for a partner to give him a little peace of mind.
- 他有一家夜总会  - 夜总会？
- He's got this nightclub to run down there. - A nightclub?
对，一家单身酒吧，靠海边
Got a singles bar. It's near the beach.
我到家里拿2个手榴弹
I got two grenades in my house.
我宁可把整个姆巴里街炸飞 我也不会离开你
I'd blow up all Mulberry Street before I'd give you up. You understand?
我不知道你要干傻事的话，我会做些什么
I don't know what I would do if you did something wrong.
我会和你同生共死，懂吗？
You understand? I'd die with you.
快跑！
Come on!
快跑！四号！
Come on, Four!
四号！
Four!
妈的！界内！
- Shit. - That was in.
胡说
Bullshit. Knocked me so far...
别惹我！
Don't push me!
我会打爆你的头
I'll break your fucking head.
- 噢，糟了！他醒了  - 你们这帮…
- Shit! He lives! - What the fuck are you...
操！
Fuck!
天哪
Jesus Christ.
半小时了
Half hour.
- 那人在哪儿？  - 我也不知道
- Where is this guy? - I don't know, Left.
- 是不是他？  - 对，就是他
- Is that him? - Yeah, that's him.
唐，你带了贵客前来
Don, you brought the cavalry.
里奇·伽佐
Richie Gazzo.
- 你好吗？  - 你好吗？
- How you doing? - How you doing?
我迟到了！
I'm late!
我想你们能好好享受日光浴了
You guys got a chance to work on your suntans out here.
它叫王庭，这儿每个人都是国王
Kings Court. Where every man is a king.
在有你自己的宴会厅前 还得等待，要学会安于现状
Wait until you get a load of the banquet room. You're gonna plotz.
问问这干嘛跟他妈垃圾场似的？
Ask him why this place is such a fucking dump.
他想知道怎么会是这样，里奇
He wants to know why it's such a dump, Richie.
我被迫关门
I had to shut the doors.
混混们像吸血似的
The way these bums had their hands in my pockets.
这个两百，那个三百…
You know, $200 for this, $300 for that.
我老婆还要干那事，懂我意思吗？
I got a wife who does that, you know what I mean?
叫他走，唐尼
Ask him to leave, Donnie.
- 里奇，出去看看车好吗？  - 好的
- Richie, step outside, take a look at the car. - Sure. Great.
居然有这种家伙吗？ 我看他连自己老婆都养不起
What kind of a man has a Malvole? He won't provide for his own wife.
- 听我说，这家伙没事  - 你敢担保吗？
- I'm telling you, this guy's all right. - You vouch for him?
- 我是说，以前认识他，他还算…  - 你替这家伙担保吗？
- When I knew him before, he was all right... - You vouch for the guy?
只是引荐一下，联营的事由你说了算
I'm just making an introduction. You got to make the decision about the joint.
说不定能行的
This would be something, you know,
你我在这儿有自己的小天地
if we had my own lounge down here, me and you.
- 想过吗？  - 桑尼会怎么想？
- You know? - What about Sonny?
唐尼，不用你教
Donnie, don't tell me what to do, Donnie.
我来问个问题
I'm asking a question.
唐尼，黑桑只是在这里度假
Donnie, Sonny's down here for a vacation.
他那也许还要享受一会儿
He ain't once gotten out of that chaise longue.
或许就像躺在他妈的吊床上
He lies there like he's in fucking traction.
是，我知道 可我也记得他曾说要开展业务什么的
Yeah, I know, but he did mention that he might wanna get something going.
如果他要插手，那会怎么样？
Imagine Sonny Black operating down here. The way he is?
得了，黑桑属于布鲁克林区
Come on. Sonny Black belongs in Brooklyn.
如果我们这里做得好
I guess if everything worked out
我们要给他送点钱去吗？
we could send a few fazools up there, no?
拼搏了三十年，我得到了什么？
Thirty years I'm busting my hump. What do I got?
就算是一条狗也有自己路边那一小块领土
Even a dog gets a warm piece of the sidewalk.
这些年我不能白干
I ought to show something for what I did.
- 你知道我意思吧？  - 当然
- You know what I mean? - Definitely.
这儿不是纽约
This ain't New York down here.
没有政治，牢骚和争斗
New York with the politics, all the old beefs and the grudges.
在这儿，我这种人能跟老板们坐在一起
Down here, a guy like me could sit down with the boss.
明白我的意思吗？
You know what I'm saying?
不再寄人篱下，自由自在
Get out from under, be a free agent again.
唐尼，非常棒
I'm telling you, Donnie, nothing but right.
老左想要得到桑托的认可
Lefty wants to ask Santo Trafficante for permission to operate down here.
- 你得为我准备条船  - 我们可没这么多钱
- You got to give me a boat. - We can't afford that kind of money.
- 什么样的船？  - 什么样我也不知道，70尺长的
- What kind of a boat? - I don't know. Like a 70-footer.
- 我只借用一天  - 那一天可得花六千元，乔
- I want to take him out for the day. - You're talking $6,000 a day here, Joe.
桑托是佛罗里达的大老板
Santo Trafficante is the boss of Florida.
- 他有权发号施令，知道吗？  - 我知道
- He sits on the Commission. Did you know? - I knew that.
- 一条70尺长的船  - 都有80尺了
- A 70-foot boat? - It's up to 80, actually.
我们窃听到老左正跟桑托的人谈这个
We just picked up Lefty on a wiretap talking to one of Trafficante's guys.
如果要起诉放高利贷的话 还有一些东西要看
A few things to go over to make a loan-sharking indictment.
可那非常重要
This is important!
九十，是的
Ninety, actually.
我已经照你说的替这个家伙担保了
I did what you asked. I came here and vouched for this guy.
然后呢，要我带桑托去玩橡皮鸭子吗？
So what, I'm gonna take Santo Trafficante out in a rubber ducky or what?
伙计，看来我们要清洁下你的嘴了
We're gonna have to wash your mouth out, bud.
沙利上头是尼克，还是尼克·西格？
Does Sally Paintglass report to Nicky or Nicky Cigars?
- 尼克·格拉斯  - 尼克·格拉斯？
- Nicky Glasses. - Nicky Glasses?
我是说我们想用RICO对付桑尼
As I was saying, we've got to fold Sonny into the RICO...
- 我要的是他妈的船！  - 我是摩门教徒，说话干净点好吗
- I need a boat for this fucking sit-down! - I'm a Mormon, mister. Now clean it up.
乔，你的录音机有毛病了
Joe, I think you got a malfunction on your tape recorder.
给我一艘船，好吗？什么？
Get me a fucking boat, would you? What?
我什么都听不见
I'm not getting anything here.
我很担心，他陷的太深了
I'm worried. He's getting strung-out.
我们会搞到证据的，干他妈的
We're getting what we want. Fuck him.
全都在这儿
There it is.
只需慢慢拿走它
Just moving behind, nice and slow.
干嘛不数数呢？伙计，数呀
Why don't you count it, my friend? Go ahead.
都在这里了，不会有错的
It's all there. No bullshit.
我们是好人吧？
We're bueno?
很高兴跟你们做生意
Pleasure doing business with you caballeros.
哦，哥伦比亚，海上的明珠
Oh, Columbia, the gem of the ocean
勇敢和自由的家园
The home of the brave and the free
- 干  - 干！
- Fuck. - Fuck!
你在干什么？你想把我扔进池子里去？
What are you doing? You want to throw me in the pool? You got the balls?
他还没想好呢
He hasn't made a pick yet.
忘了这些狗
Forget those dogs.
嗨，如果你现在量我血压
Hey, you know, if you took my blood pressure right now,
肯定完全正常了
it'd be down 100%.
还好鲁斯提在坐牢
Rusty's locked up in the can with his fucking sinuses.
要是他发现你们在佛罗里达
He finds out you're down in Florida...
我才不鸟他
I don't punch a clock for Rusty.
在这里要像爷们一样
Live your life like a man down here.
算了吧，桑尼，到了明天
Forget about it, Sonny. By tomorrow,
你就会为吃不到纽约的面包而哭了
you're gonna be crying you miss the New York bread.
纽约的面包象蛋糕
New York bread is like cake.
嗨，2周了，你还穿着同样的衬衣
Hey, two weeks you're wearing the same fucking shirt.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
我又不着急赶回纽约去
I'm not in a big hurry to go back to New York.
是啊，别担心这个，再过一天
Yeah, don't worry about it. One more day,
那衬衣就会自己跑回纽约去了
that fucking shirt's gonna go back to New York on its own.
那是我不要联合服务的原因了
That's why we don't get service in this joint.
他们肯定会说，太脏了，拒绝服务
They see you in that fucking shirt, they say, "There's Joe Faccia Di Culo," in that shirt.
够了
That's enough.
够了？够了是什么意思？
"That's enough?" What does that mean, "that's enough"?
看看，他生气了
Look at him, look at him. He's mad.
- 嗨，唐尼，我们去走走  - 去哪儿？
- Hey, Donnie, let's go for a walk. - Where?
- 走，我们去酒吧  - 好
- Come on, I'm gonna get a candy bar. - All right.
看他，那件衬衣本来是黄色的
Look at him, that was once yellow, that shirt.
我们现在得怎么称呼他？佛罗里达的桑尼
What are we supposed to call him now? Sonny Florida.
小心，别真把他惹火了
Watch out, you're gonna put him on the warpath again.
是的
Yeah.
那件衬衣，简直就是理发师给你绑的破布
That shirt. That's the shirt the barber gives you to put over your shirt.
我想知道你干什么去了
I want to know what you're up to.
- 什么意思？  - 昨天
- What do you mean? - Yesterday.
昨晚？
Last night?
昨晚你在干什么？
What were you doing last night?
我说昨天什么时候？昨晚什么时候？
No, I'm saying, when yesterday? What time yesterday?
到这里来，想糊弄我
Come here. Don't mess around with me. Yesterday fucking afternoon.
什么也没做
Nothing.
为什么左撇子这么希望我回纽约？
Why has Lefty got such a hard-on to send me back to New York?
得了，桑尼，那家伙在耍你玩呢
Oh, come on, Sonny. That guy's busting your balls down there.
我想知道
I wanna know.
我想知道你们到底在这里搞什么
I wanna know what you got going on down here.
我不懂，桑尼
I don't understand, Sonny.
我们赚点说不出口的零钱 你都要一一过问吗？
You wanna know about every half-assed scam that'll amount to nothing?
没错
That's right.
听着
Look.
我没有任何冒犯的意思
I don't mean any disrespect.
我的意思是，我知道你是大哥 而我微不足道
I mean, I know you're a skipper and I'm a nobody,
但是我不能把老左卖了
but I can't do that to Lefty.
听着，鸟人，小心我做了你
Listen to me, you cocksucker, I'll eat your fucking balls for breakfast.
你明白吗？你们每一个人
You understand me? Every fucking one of you.
这是性命攸关的事，不是什么该死的游戏
This is life or death. Not a fucking game, Donnie.
这是我说的这样，现在，你告诉我
This is my say-so. Now, you tell me.
我做不到，桑尼
I can't do it, Sonny.
要是我现在就做了你
How about if I fucking whack you right here and now?
你想怎么样就怎么样吧
Do what you have to do, Sonny.
我不能出卖老左
I can't do that to Lefty.
- 妈妈，帮帮我好吗？  - 你好？
- Mommy, I need some help. - Hello?
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
- 太紧了  - 我来了，宝贝
- It's too tight. - Here, sweetie.
- 我在佛罗里达  - 你在佛罗里达干嘛？
- I'm in Florida. - What are you doing in Florida?
我也不知道，算是钓海龟吧
I don't know. I'm hunting for turtles.
你以为我在干什么？我是在工作
What do you think I'm doing in Florida? Honey, I'm working.
今天只有12度，把外套穿上
It's 12 degrees here. Excuse me, you're wearing this coat!
年轻的小姐，你得把外套穿上
Young lady, you are wearing this coat.
- 婊子  - 你说什么？
- Bitch. - What did you call me?
- 家里还好吧？  - 你刚才说什么？
- Is everything all right? - What did you...
我要是说不好又怎样？会有什么不同吗？
What if I said no, Joe? Would it make any difference?
- 恐怕不会？  - 那就别问了，过来，起来
- I guess not. - So don't ask me. Come on, stand up.
约翰·伟恩死了，举国哀掉
"John Wayne dead. Nation mourns."
他怎么会死呢？
How can John Wayne die?
跟印第安人有关吧
The fucking Indians got him.
他是个保守专制的男人
"Old-fashioned family man. Ruled with an iron hand."
你看
Look at that.
让我跟凯莉谈谈圣餐礼的事吧
Let me talk to Kerry. I want to talk about the Communion.
噢，拜托，她都不想参加了
My God, Joe. She doesn't want to do it.
你说什么？她不能说不去就不去
What do you mean? She ain't got no choice.
- 快把外套穿好  - 把电话给她，玛吉
- You are wearing this coat! - Put her on the phone, Maggie.
我不知道几时再能给你电话 她知道不要吃圣餐吗？
I don't know when I can call again. Does she know not to bite the wafer?
我不知道，但是她已经决定了
I don't know. She's acting out or something.
- 我下周回来一趟  - 多谢
- I'll be back next week. - Thank you.
我答应你一定回来带她去圣餐礼
Maggie, I promise I'll get back for her Communion.
- 你那件看来也不行  - 别和你妹妹闹
- Yours doesn't look any better. - Don't start it with your sister.
- 乔，我要出去了  - 什么？
- Joe, I got to go. - What?
我爱你，噢，真是的
I love you. Shit.
- 给谁打电话？里奇吗？ - 不是，桑尼说什么啦？
- Who's that on the phone? Richie? - No. What did Sonny say?
- 跟桑尼说酒吧的事啦？ - 没有，我还以为你说了
- You told Sonny about the club? - No, I thought you did.
- 别提起就是了，打电话给里奇吧  - 好的
- Just shut up about it. Call Richie. - All right.
像桑托那些人物
Big guy like Santo Trafficante, he's been around
自从小胡子比兹之后就是老板
since the Mustache Petes.
你要尊敬他
You gotta respect the man.
- 唐尼，你弄到船了吗？  - 没，我正在想办法
- Donnie, you get that boat yet? - No, I'm working on it.
别说不行，你要想办法搞定
Don't tell me no. You got to get that boat.
我已找过他们了，他手下人说他很喜欢船
I reached out already. His man says, "Lefty, he loves boats."
我跟他说是一百尺的大船
I told him a 100-foot boat. I'm on the clothesline now.
我知道，我正在想办法
I told you, I'm working on it.
- 你可别让我失望  - 我让你失望过吗？
- Don't disappoint me again, please. - Again? Since when did I disappoint you?
得了吧！这是什么？
Forget about it. What's this?
噢，你看，我们可以互相寄送
Look at that. Same thing we call each other.
对，我的朋友，我们的朋友，对
Friend of mine, friend of ours. Good.
它是双关语，你知道吗？
But there's the double meaning. You get it?
- 懂我的意思吗？ - 是的
- Know what I mean? - Yeah.
- 做老板的会喜欢的  - 是的
- A boss appreciates a thing like that. - Yeah.
- 很有讽刺意味  - 是的
- The irony of it. - Yeah, irony.
别提了，再放个小礼物进去
Forget about it. Put a beaner inside here,
这样他就知道我们都是好样的
then he knows these are men of men.
我在想办法的时候
You see, if I work out the strategy right,
你也要提出你的意见
you got to hold up your end now.
- 懂我的意思吗？ - 是的
- You know what I'm saying? - Yeah, I know.
懂我的意思吗？
You got to hold up your end now. You know what I'm saying?
这个多少钱？唐尼，你要吗？
How much is this? Donnie, you got something on you?
- 你在干什么？  - 5元怎么样？
- What are you doing there? - How about here's $5?
- 你干的很棒  - 什么？
- You're doing an amazing job, you know. - What?
- 我们都是这样想的  - 是的，绝对是
- I mean, we all think so. - Yeah. Absolutely.
真想大叫几声
For crying out loud. Fuck.
- 能问你一个问题吗？  - 什么问题？
- Can I ask you something? - What?
什么是“得了吧”？什么意思？
What's "forget about it"? What is that?
“得了吧”，就是说…
"Forget about it" is like
如果你认同别人说…
if you agree with someone.
象拉古是个大傻瓜，你就说得了吧
Like, "Raquel Welch is one great piece of ass." "Forget about it."
有时别人说林肯比卡迪拉克好
But then, if you disagree, like, "A Lincoln is better than a Cadillac?
你不同意时你就说得了吧
"Forget about it."
又比如对世界上最棒的东西
It's also like if something is the greatest thing in the world.
这胡椒！得了吧，懂了吗？
Like "Minghia, those peppers! Forget about it!" You know?
有时它跟说见鬼去吧差不多
It's also like saying, "Go to hell," too.
比如说鲍利，你那东西只有一寸长 鲍利就可以说得了吧
Like, "Paulie, you got a one-inch pecker." And Paulie says, "Forget about it."
得了吧，鲍利，得了吧
Forget about it. "Paulie, forget about it."
有时它就是指忘了这事吧
Sometimes it just means, forget about it.
好了，太感谢了，我懂了
All right. Thank you very much. I got it.
告诉你们，要是我还没给老左弄到船
Let me tell you something. I don't get this boat for Lefty...
- 什么？又得了吧  - 真他妈得了吧？
- Forget about it? - Fucking forget about it.
你知道那个行动吗？叫什么来着？
You know that sting operation? What do you call it?
就是穿的像阿拉伯人去行贿议员？
Where the agents dress up like Arabs and try to bribe congressmen?
- 他们有条船在这儿  - 什么？
- They got a boat down here. - What?
- “阿拉伯人贿赂号”  - 太好了，就是阿巴斯康号
- Abscam. - That's right. It's Abscam.
是吗？我们能弄到它？
Yeah? Could we get it?
得了吧
Forget about it.
狗娘养的！
Son of a bitch!
来吧，狗娘…
Come on, son of...
他妈的唐尼
Fucking Donnie.
嗨，老左，你不会相信这些的
Hey, Lefty, you're not gonna fucking believe this.
- 你在给我开玩笑，是吗？  - 什么？
- You think this is some joke, huh? - What?
- 你认为这很好玩？  - 你在说什么？
- You think this is funny, huh? - What are you talking about?
这太他妈冷了，为什么这里这么冷？
It's fucking cold. Why is it so cold in here?
听我说，唐尼，我知道你知道，对吧
Hey, Donnie. Listen to me, Donnie. I know you know, all right?
而我知道你知道我知道你知道
And I know you know I know you know.
- 对  - 对
- Right. - Right.
你在说什么？
What the fuck are you talking about?
我在说，我快他妈的冻死了，唐尼
I'm telling you, I'm freezing to my fucking death, Donnie.
是啊，这里简直就是格陵兰岛
Yeah, fucking Greenland in here.
这里没有按钮，按钮去哪儿了？
There's no knob. Where's the knob?
谢谢
Thank you.
那么，你要找维修工吗？他们有…
Well, did you call the maintenance guy? They gotta have a...
维修工，我可不要维修工，你怎么，疯了？
Maintenance. I'm not gonna call a maintenance guy. What are you, crazy?
谁知道维修工是不是一个特工？来吧
Who knows a maintenance guy comes in, what if he's an agent? Come on.
得了吧，他不是特工，他是他妈的清洁工
Come on, he's not an agent. He's a fucking janitor.
清洁工，进来，我不想让他碰
Janitor, come on. I don't want him touching it.
放下你的手，谁知道他会在空调里装什么
Put his hands on it. Who knows what he puts in the goddamn air-conditioner.
这里，看这个，这里，看，我把它调高，来
Here, look at this. Here, look, look. I got it up to 120, here. Come on.
我不会再让任何人来这里了
Ain't no fucking... I'm not gonna have anyone going in here.
你知道什么？那真是一个他妈的笑话
You know something? That's a fucking practical joke.
- 那就是那样的  - 是个笑话？
- That's what that is. - It's a joke?
- 是的  - 在哪里？我没听见笑话
- Yeah. - Where's the joke? I don't see the joke.
得了，你知道桑尼的幽默感 这就是他妈的桑尼的杰作
Come on, you know Sonny's sense of humor. It's Sonny fucking around.
- 你认为这是桑尼干的  - 是的
- You think this is Sonny? - Yeah.
- 桑尼？  - 是的
- Sonny? - Yeah.
桑尼这样对我？不是黑桑，我告诉你
Sonny did this to me? This is not Sonny Black, my friend.
不，这是你，唐尼，你他妈个鸟人，是你吗？
No. This is you, Donnie. You fucking cocksucker, it's you!
喂，别这样叫我，老左
Whoa, you don't fucking call me that, Lefty.
- 不要叫你什么？  - 不要叫我鸟人
- Don't call you what? - Don't you fucking call me cocksucker.
鸟人，我想怎么叫都行，我还会叫你鸟人
Cocksucker. I'll call you anything I want. I'll call you cocksucker.
对，我要叫你鸟人的我还会叫你去干你娘
Yeah, I'll call you cocksucker. I'll call you motherfucker!
对，你才是一个他妈的鸟人
Yeah, you're a fucking cocksucker.
- 你叫我鸟人？  - 是的，你喜欢吗？
- You calling me a cocksucker? - Yeah, you like that?
- 我是什么？  - 鸟人
- I'm a what? - Cocksucker.
- 我是鸟人？  - 你是鸟人
- I'm a cocksucker? - You're a cocksucker.
你打算做什么？你想杀了我？
What are you gonna do? You're gonna kill me over a fucking draft?
- 是的  - 我告诉你
- Yeah. - Let me tell you something.
你最好他妈的杀了我
You'd better fucking kill me.
因为你今晚不杀了我，我会再来这里
Because you don't kill me tonight, I'm gonna come in here,
我会剁碎你…我会埋伏在这里然后杀了你
I'm gonna chop you up and then... I'll sneak in here and fucking kill you.
哦，是吗，你别叫我鸟人
Oh yeah, you don't call me cocksucker.
这里
Here.
哦，来啊，来啊
Oh, yeah, go ahead.
- 鸟人  - 听着，把话收回
- Cocksucker. - Go ahead. Take it back.
- 那你杀了我  - 把它收回，唐尼
- Kill me. - Take it back, Donnie.
去你的，我要回自己的房间了
Fuck you, I'm getting my own room.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
你明天见不到我了，我告诉你
You're not gonna see me tomorrow, for your information.
我告诉你，你明天见不着我了
I got news for you, Donnie. You won't see me tomorrow.
明天是母亲节
Tomorrow is Mother's Day,
而聪明的家伙母亲节是不工作的！
and wise guys don't work on Mother's Day!
你个鸟人
You're a cocksucker.
随你便！
Go ahead!
不！
No!
饶了我吧！不！
Give me a break! No!
你穿那破衣服是想害死我吗？
Are you trying to get me killed with that fucking suit?
还有那该死的车，紫色的
Fucking car. That purple, fucking car.
别提“兴奋”二字，懂吗？是的
Don't say the word "plotz." You understand?
先拿到后面去
Get in the back.
等一等，我马上就来
Wait a minute. I'll be there.
桑托先生，这是老左，我们的朋友
Mr. Trafficante, this is Lefty, a friend of ours.
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know what to say.
这是我一生最伟大的时刻
To me, this is like a great moment in my life.
这就像一次盛会
It's like meeting Mickey Mantle.
这是我专为你准备的，桑托先生
That's the boat I arranged for you, Mr. Trafficante.
上面一应俱全，酒吧和你喜欢的音乐
It's got everything. Got a full bar, any kind of music you want.
想打个电话吗？上面有
You want to make a telephone, it's got telephones.
- 还有什么问题吗  - 桑尼在哪儿？
- Any questions, you ask me. - Where's Sonny Black?
- 黑桑尼吗？  - 是的
- Sonny Black? - Yeah.
大家下车吧，来吧，宝贝
Everybody, out. Come on, baby.
- 太棒了！ - 没骗你吧
- It's beautiful! - What did I tell you?
带家人来啦？喂，鲍利，你知道吗
You brought the family. Hey, Paul, what do you know?
- 船真漂亮 - 你说呢，鲍利？
- Nice boat. - What do you say, Paulie?
姬丽安在哪里？
Where's Gilligan?
这才是我想要的那种船
Now, that's what I call a boat.
是的，呃…是
Yeah, I would be... Yeah.
给
Here.
你要在这里经营，你得知道点规矩
Sure, you can operate here. You got to show a little respect.
嗨，这边
Hey! Over here.
我实在不想看到你
I don't even want to look at you.
- 你知道什么是两面派？  - 我又怎么了？
- You know what the bow is? - What did I do now?
你是个阴险的小人
You stabbed the wrong guy in the back, my friend.
什么？你以为我告诉黑桑的？
What are you talking about? You think I said something to Sonny?
到船头去吧，我就呆在这儿
Go to the bow. I'm gonna stay in the stern.
过去吧，去啊
Go to the bow. Stay there.
我很讨厌你，懂吗？
I'm so disgusted with you, you know that?
- 是的，刚说过这话  - 就是如此
- You just said it. - Just so you know.
- 在这儿做什么？  - 桑托先生和你想的不同
- How you doing? - That Trafficante is something else.
- 是个不错的老头，是吗？ - 得了吧
- Is that right? Is he a good old guy? - Forget about it.
那老家伙已经经营了50多年
That motherfucker had this all to himself for 50 fucking years
可这里还是像个农村
and it's still a cow town.
这里本该发达的像拉斯维加斯了
This could be like Vegas down here.
去他妈的红桑和泽西
Forget about Sonny Red and his trucks in Jersey.
佛罗里达才是我想要的
This is all I want. Florida.
我告诉你，红桑现在肯定蛋都冻硬了
Tell you something. Sonny Red is freezing his nuts off right now.
那是
That's for sure.
我只要路斯提给我一点经费
All I need is the start-up money from Rusty
等我们有钱了，你想怎样呢？
and then we all get rich.
等我们有钱了，我们要回纽约吗？
Are we heading back to New York pretty soon?
你就不用了，我要你在这里管事
Not you. I want you to represent me down here, Donnie.
我要让你在这儿为我做事
I want you to be my man in Florida.
去掌管那酒吧，就是那个“王庭”
Get that club going. You know, Kings Court.
你在想我怎么会知道的，是吗？
You didn't think I knew about that, did you?
我想我会把狮子交给你
I think I'll send the lion down here with you.
把它养在停车场里
Keep that big pussy in the parking lot.
你知道的桑尼，我真的很感激你的好意…
You know, Sonny, I really appreciate the offer and everything,
但我在纽约还有些事要处理
but I got a lot of things going on in New York.
- 我还要回去  - 你也知道老左，很厚道的一个人
- I'd like to keep them... - Lefty's a dynamite guy. No doubt about it.
我在狱中时他照顾过我
He looked after me when I was in the can.
那些事我不会忘的
That's something I don't forget,
有些甚至终身难忘
something that I will never ever forget.
他很讲义气，他真的很关心你
He's a stand-up guy. He really cares about you, too.
我知道的
Yeah, I know he does.
但…问题是你认为他在帮你
The problem is that you think that he's helping you,
实际他也在拖你后腿
but he's hurting you.
他有时候搞不清状况
He gets those two or three wines in him...
知道我的意思吗？
You know what I'm saying.
我不想踩着别人往上爬，不会的
I don't want to be stepping on nobody's toes.
- 如果不是因为老左，我…  - 那是的
- If it wasn't for Left, I... - That's it. Look.
你现在是我的人了
You belong to me now.
就这样了
That's it.
桑托要走了
Mr. Trafficante's leaving.
- 你说呢？  - 天哪，他们笑死人了
- You believe that? - Ulcers, Christ, they're killing me.
过来
Come here.
桑托，这是唐尼
Santo, this is Donnie.
- 我们的朋友  - 见到你很高兴
- He's a friend of ours. - Hi, Donnie. Nice to meet you.
- 这是唐尼  - 你好吗
- This is Donnie. - Hi, how you doing?
- 替我向乔问好  - 我会的
- Give my best to Joe, will you? - I will.
他被雪困住了，你能想象吗？
Snowed in. Can you believe him?
过分，女儿的第一次圣餐礼他都不回家
Right. His daughter's First Communion, and he gets stuck at an airport.
雪太大，不安全，再见，好吗？
That's for his own protection. I'll see you later. Okay?
- 我讨厌坐飞机  - 路上小心
- I hate flying. - I know you do. Be safe.
噢，心肝
Oh, sweetheart.
宝贝
Honey.
你爸爸为你骄傲
Your father is so proud of you.
我上楼了
I'm going upstairs.
该死的，乔
God damn it, Joe.
该号码已经变更
The number you have dialed has been changed.
该用户要求不提供新号码
The new number is unpublished at the subscriber's request.
老左，去办下手续好吗？
Hey, Left, get us checked in over there, will you?
- 嗨，别走开，我去买张报纸  - 好的
- Stick around. I'm going to get a paper. - All right.
天哪，霍兹曼律师走过来了
Jesus, Joe. That's Hollman, US Attorney, coming at us.
正向这边来了，怎么办？
The guy on the right. Christ, Joe, what are we going to do?
你干嘛不闭嘴？我会搞定的
Why don't you just shut the fuck up? I'll take care of it.
有任何事
Anything goes wrong down there,
让他们找纽约的人搞定
you have their people call your people in New York, understand?
不要芝麻大的事情都让我出面
I don't want to come down here and iron anything out.
- 你的机票呢？  - 乔·皮斯顿
- You got your plane tickets? - Joe Pistone.
你不记得我吗？从南部来的…
Remember me? Southern District...
你他妈的找死吗？
What kind of fucking shit...
- 你在干什么？  - 这他妈神经病！
- What are you doing? - Grabbed my cock.
我操！
What the fuck!
别出声！他在执行任务
Shut up. He's working. Keep your mouth shut.
变态杂种！敢来碰我！
Fucking degenerate bastard. What a sick fuck. Grabbed my cock.
我要把酒吧经营的好些 久点也没关系，懂吗
I want that club up and running. I don't care how long it takes.
有警察来了，快走
Here comes a fucking cop. Get the hell out of here.
小心点，票和东西拿好了吗？
Have a safe trip. You have the tickets and everything?
听我说
Listen to me.
去打个电话，我要乘下班飞机回来，明白？
Get on the phone. Get me on the next flight back. Understand?
再叫我乔，我会割断你的喉咙，明白吗？
Don't call me Joe again. I'll cut your fucking throat, understand?
这个杂种！
You piece of shit.
- 爸爸？  - 嘿，宝贝
- Daddy? - Hi, baby.
- 谁创造了你？  - 上帝创造了我
- Who made you? - God made me.
- 上帝为什么创造你？  - 上帝为了显示他的仁慈
- Why did God make you? - God made me to show his goodness
他给我欢乐
to make me happy with him in heaven.
- 上帝在哪？ - 上帝无处不在
- Where is God? - God is everywhere.
做个美梦吧，我的天使
Sweet dreams, angel.
我要离婚
I want a divorce.
他总是不回家
He comes home at all hours of the night
三个月来，他去了哪儿，在做什么 我一概不知
without announcing when, why, or where he's been for the last three months.
你知道他做了什么？他重新整理了橱柜
And you know what he does? He rearranges the cabinets.
他重新铺了床，用吸尘器清理了房间
He remakes the bed. He vacuums the entire house.
见过有男人用吸尘器的吗？那是不正常的
Do you know another man that vacuums? It's abnormal.
- 太不正常了  - 那你改电话号码…
- It's abnormal behavior. - Well, you know,
却不告诉丈夫是正常的吗？
changing the phone number and not telling your husband is pretty normal.
- 我不见你，你也别见我  - 现在我知道是什么感觉了
- I don't exist, you don't exist. - So now I know how it feels.
不，我告诉你，我现在感觉好极了
No, now I know how you feel. I'll tell you something. It felt good.
我现在知道控制着别人是什么感觉
Now I do know how it feels to be so in control.
我知道强势是什么感觉
Now I know how it feels to be strong.
- 你喜换控制别人吗？  - 噢，天哪
- You love control, don't you? - Oh, my God.
请你听着，乔
Please, Joe, just listen.
让她先说，不然没完没了了
Otherwise you just play out the old pathology.
玛吉，你说乔常不在家
Maggie, you were saying Joe leaves.
是这样的
Yes, he leaves.
他把房子扔给我，替我和孩子付账
He leaves me with the house
可是这样并不是一个丈夫
and the kids and the bills, but not a husband.
我需要的是丈夫
I want my husband.
你是在逃避什么？
What do you think you're running from?
- 我没逃避什么  - 没逃避什么？
- I ain't running from nothing. - "I ain't running from nothing."
听到了吗？好歹你也读过大学
You hear yourself? The man I married was a college man.
距离迫使玛吉开始充当追逐者的角色
Being the distancer forces Maggie into the role of the pursuer.
她开始觉得拥有权力
This gives you a feeling of power.
而你，却又开始反感
Simultaneously, you resent Maggie
- 玛吉的生理需要  - 我是FBI密探，医生
- for fulfilling her intimacy needs... - I'm an undercover agent for the FBI, Doctor.
你跟黑手党的家伙狼狈为奸
You and your Mafia faggots can go screw each other.
我不管了
I'm not gonna do it anymore.
我真希望你能帮她
I really hope that you can help her out
明明是她有问题，她才需要治疗
because obviously she's very sick. You can see that.
对，是我有病
Obviously, I'm the sick one.
- 你  - 这样吧
- You. - Now,
星期一，三，五是你的亲切请求日
Monday, Wednesday, and Friday are Joe's intimacy days.
二，四，六是玛吉的
Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday are Maggie's.
你们要在自己的日期向对方亲切的请求
Now, on your day, you make an intimacy request.
比如帮我按摩一下了，或者别的什么
"Rub my back," or
孩子们真麻烦，能协助我吗？
"I have a problem with the kids. Could you help me out?"
你无忧无虑住在安全的屋子里
You sit around in your safe little fucking house
坐着安全的小车，和你那些狗屁朋友
with your safe little fucking station wagon, and your safe little friends.
一百一百的拿钱
You dream up the next $100 head fuck.
- 什么帮我按摩？  - 你这没良心的
- "Will you rub my back?" - You're an animal, do you know that?
- 快上车去吧  - 你知道吗？嗯？
- Just get in the fucking car. - Do you know that?
知道我想怎么提出亲切的请求？
You know what my intimacy request is for that guy?
非常亲切
It's very intimate.
我要把他给我的账单塞他屁眼里
He can take the bill he's gonna send me and shove it up his ass.
你知道我们为什么要找他吗？
You want to know why we went to him?
我希望他有个可以让我不离开的理由
I was hoping he could come up with one good reason for me not to leave you
因为我找不到
because I don't have one anymore.
什么？你想离开我？
What? You gonna leave me?
你想离开我，玛吉？你别离开我
You gonna leave me, Maggie? You don't leave me.
- 喂  - 喂，安妮特
- Hello. - Hey, Annette.
唐尼！
Donnie.
- 什么事？  - 你在哪儿？
- What's the matter? - Where are you?
我在纽约，我不得不回来，怎么了？
I'm in New York. I had to come back. Why?
- 汤米…  - 怎么？出什么事了？
- It's Tommy. - Why, what's going on? What happened?
给你妹妹夹点蔬菜好吗？谢谢
Can you give your sister some vegetables, honey? Thank you.
别用手，宝贝，还要什么吗？
Not with your fingers, sweetie. What else do you need?
我们今天上课学分数，知道吗？
We did fractions with Miss Greenberg today in class, you know?
是吗？分数？
Did you? Fractions?
- 我测验得了95分  - 好样的
- I got my test back and I got a 95. - Of course you did.
- 出什么事了？  - 你来这做什么？
- What's going on? - Donnie, what are you doing here?
你不是应该在佛罗里达了么
You belong in Florida.
我听安妮特说了
I checked in with Annette and she said something...
- 你从佛州打电话给她的吗？  - 就在这儿，我有些事要办
- You called her from Florida? - I was up here. I had a few things to care of.
唐尼，你得回去
You got to go back. Come on.
他没事吧？他还好吧？
What happened to him? Is he gonna be all right?
我不清楚？
Do I know?
他们挂了十二张图在墙上 却他妈的什么也不说
They got 12 fucking diplomas on the wall, and they can't tell you a fucking thing.
得了吧，就算汤米能出院
Forget about it. Tommy gets out of this fucking Bellevue,
立刻又得回去
he's going right back to fucking up.
- 他究竟怎么了？嗑药过量？  - 不是这样
- What did he do? Did he overdose? - That ain't the question.
嘴上插着塑料管
A plastic pipe in his mouth.
无数根管子，还要靠机器呼吸
About five million tubes. They have a machine breathing for him.
医生在哪儿？要我帮你找那些家伙谈谈吗？
Where's the fucking doctor? You want me to go talk to this guy for you?
找医生又能怎样？打断他的腿吗
Talk to the doctor? You gonna break his legs?
我是说我在这儿能帮你做点什么
I'm saying, you want me to do something? I'm here.
是的，我要你回佛罗里达
I want you to go back down to Florida.
你现在是桑尼的人了，听话吧
You belong to Sonny now. Believe me.
我来这儿就是想帮帮你
I came here to be with you. I want to help you out.
- 你是我兄弟，我来帮你  - 我不用你过来
- You're my man. I'm here for you. - I don't want you here, Donnie.
你和汤米一样，都不愿听别人的话
You and Tommy is both peas in a fucking pod. You don't listen.
你们自己主意很大
You got your own ideas.
你们总是自以为是，什么都不当回事
You do what you want to do up on your high horses. Everything's a joke.
你还是回…
You go to La Guardia and you get back.
- 回佛罗里达去，坐飞机去  - 我不走
- Get back to Florida. Get on a plane. - I ain't going.
- 你得了吧  - 快滚
- Forget about it. - Go on!
我要留下陪你，你想教训我吗？
I'm gonna stay here with you. You want to kick the shit out of me?
我就坐在这儿，怎么样？
I'm gonna be right here. All right?
二十八年
Twenty eight years.
出生证上都写着
You can read it on his birth certificate.
贝尔维尤医院出生，现在要从这儿…回去了
Bellevue Hospital. Now he's back, in there.
我现在担心的要死
And I'm out here, worried to my fucking death.
他现在躺在那儿 又跟二十八年前一样混沌未开了
And he's asleep in there, same as 28 years ago
还是一样
with the same expression.
一点没变化
He's made no progress.
这小子一点不知道上进
He ain't got no fucking respect.
他是我儿子
He's my son.
他的心脏像手表一样停止了跳动
His heart stopped like a watch.
医生说的，就像手表一样
That's what the doctor said. Just like a watch.
他们用尽所有方法把他救活
They had to wind it back up.
谁知道呢？也许下一次
Who knows? Maybe next time,
就救不了了
they can't.
他会好起来的，他会好起来的
He's gonna be all right. He'll be all right.
我爱你，唐尼
I love you, Donnie.
嗨，乔
Hey, Joe.
什么
What?
你知道美国政府？
You know the U.S. Government?
知道啊
Yeah.
那个你宣誓用生命效忠的政府?
The U.S. Government you swore an oath and dedicated your life to?
是的，为什么？
Yeah. Why?
要查我们税
We got audited.
嗨，我们敬桑尼一杯？
Hey, let's make a toast to Sonny, huh?
为桑尼和我们佛罗里达的新事业
To Sonny and our new Florida business.
嗨，桑尼，你好吗？
Hey, Sonny, how you doing?
- 怎么了，老红  - 你认识他们
- What's going on, Red? - You know the boys.
我听说你去佛罗里达了
I hear you was in Florida.
是的，那里非常好，阳光很充足
Yeah, it's nice down there. Take the sun.
你在那里有朋友了吗？
You got friends down there?
那里的人都不错
Everybody's nice down there.
他们非常友好
The people, they're very friendly down there.
效果不错
Nice color.
谢谢
Thank you.
我没有去和调查局说，没什么调查局
I'm not talking to the Bureau. There is no Bureau.
只有一群税务局混蛋和其他的混蛋
There's a bunch of assholes and the I.R.S. Is another bunch of assholes.
我要你打个电话给混蛋，你这个混蛋
So what I'm asking you to do is to place a phone call, asshole to asshole.
- 冷静点  - 你要我冷静？
- Please calm down. - You want me to calm down?
你告诉这该死的查税员，我现在要去华盛顿
You tell this fucking auditor that I'm coming to D.C.
我会把他连计算器一起抽烂，你懂吗？
And I'm gonna whip the shit out of him with his calculator, you understand?
我们冷静一下，他们不是来征…
Let's face it, bud, they don't audit you for...
那么，我挂了
Okay, I'm gonna hang up now.
等等，我级别比你高，你
Wait, I'm a GS-15. You can't...
该死的混蛋
Fucking cocksucker.
好了
All right!
你好吗，尼克？
How you doing, Nicky?
嘿，桑尼！
Hey, Sonny!
瞧这地方，真是难以置信
Look at this place. It's unbelievable.
- 真漂亮  - 今晚运气不错
- Beautiful. - I feel lucky tonight.
开张志喜
Look at it. Opening night.
这简直就是神殿
This place is a goddamn palace, for Christ's sake.
非常好，桑尼，我很喜欢
Terrific, Sonny. I love it.
- 真是好地方！  - 你好吗？
- It's a fucking palace! - How you doing?
你好吗？玩的开心吗？
How you doing? Having fun?
我们再来一次，再来
Let's try another one. Again.
我喜欢
I like it.
我喜欢这一刻
I like it bigtime.
- 我需要一份牛排，五分熟  - 辣椒多点，我喜欢辣的
- I need a steak, medium rare. - Couple bowls of chili, extra hot.
好了，唐尼，你拿着
Okay, Donnie, this is the take.
- 去把它藏好  - 好的
- Put this bag someplace safe. - All right.
鸡肉卷
Chicken taco.
慢慢转过来
Just turn real slow.
有什么问题吗，警官？
Is there a problem, Officer?
- 名字？  - 唐尼·布拉斯科，你呢？
- What's your name, boy? - Donnie Brasco. What's yours?
你们从纽约跑到这来干什么？
What are all you New York guineas doing down here?
尊夫人邀请我们来的
Your missus invited us.
先生们，这是合法的慈善晚会
Gentlemen, we're running a charity event here.
- 我们有许可  - 那狮子也合法吗？
- We have a permit. - You got a permit for the lion?
别吵了！
Break it up! Break it up!
你是猪啊
You fucking pigs!
你的保护费都付到哪儿去了？
I guess you didn't ever think of paying these guys off, did you?
谁给我去贿赂警察的钱，谁会批准我这样做？
Where the hell am I gonna get money to go bribing cops? Nobody authorized that.
知道我有多丢脸吗？
You know how fucking embarrassed I am?
老板的人也都在
The old man's people down here.
这下我能在家里躲上一年了
A year now, I got to be in my house with the shades drawn.
那包呢？
Where's that bag?
被拿走了，全都拿走了
They got it. They got everything.
那是鲁斯提的钱
That's Rusty's money.
- 桑尼，对不起  - 闭嘴！
- Sonny, I'm sorry... - Shut up.
你闭嘴，坐下！
You shut up. Sit down.
闭上你的臭嘴！
Shut the fuck up.
现在，我要回纽约
Like this, I got to go back to New York.
去跟鲁斯提谈谈
Make this right with Rusty.
去找红桑那老混蛋
Face that cocksucker Sonny Red.
你们知道我说的什么意思
You know, I got to say something.
通常警察是蠢到…
Usually the cops are so fucking dumb.
事情过了三个月他们才会得到消息
It takes them three months just to get wind something's going on.
然后他们才去申请文件
Then they got to go get a warrant.
然后还要去拍照什么…他们是谁？
They got to go through them pictures. What are they?
- 监视  - 他们要监视
- Surveillance. - They go to surveillance.
拍3个月的照片
Three months taking pictures.
为什么这次他们会知道这么多？
All this time, how do these cops know so much?
- 我们才刚开张…  - 你觉得呢？
- We just opened the fucking doors. - What are you saying?
一定是有人卧底
There's got to be a snitch here.
是的
All right.
肯定有人卧底
So there's a snitch.
我们要砍下他的老二
We find him. We cut his prick off.
塞进他嘴里，把他扔到街上
Leave it in his mouth. Leave him on the street.
好
Okay?
你怎么了，突然哑巴了？
What are you, a silent partner all of a sudden?
- 让我出去  - 嗨，老实点！
- Get me the fuck out of here! - Hey, knock it off in there!
闭嘴！
Shut up! Fuck you!
闭嘴，小子，再闹我关你小黑屋
Keep it up, boy, I'll send you out of here in a box.
- 搞定了吗？  - 搞定了
- Did you bust it up good? - Yeah, we busted it up.
他已经出局了
He's out of business. You understand?
我正在听
Yeah, I'm listening.
那小子已经完蛋了，是的
That punk is finished down here. That's it.
太好了，难以置信
That's great. I can't believe it.
- 好，那我们稍后再谈  - 好
- All right, look, I'll talk to you later. - Okay.
给我一些奶酪和腊肠
Give me some of that cheese with that salami, please?
- 他的酒吧完蛋了  - 好极了
- He busted up the club. - Good.
- 给我别的  - 给你
- Take this taste out of my mouth. - There you go.
现在他有麻烦了
Now he has to answer for what happened.
你要请他吗？
You gonna send for him?
让他过来谈谈
He sits down with us.
叭叭…就搞定了
Bing-bada-boom, it's done.
全部的人马
The whole fucking crew. All of them.
我去准备枪
I'll dust off the guns.
餐巾和桌布，五百
Napkins and tablecloths, $500 scoot.
五百？
$500 scoot?
在佛罗里达，一小时就有五百进账
Down in Florida, it's $500 an hour.
这么喜欢那里，干嘛不买些橙子纪念下？
You like it down there so much, why don't you go buy some oranges?
- 你那里怎么样，牛蛙？  - 生意冷清
- What do you got there, Bullfrog? - Dime on the vig.
我们已经尽力了，桑尼
I'm doing the best I can, Sonny.
你都干了什么，尼克？
What do you got, Nicky?
我一个兄弟搞到30多张音乐会的票
I got a guy boosted 30 tickets to Chaka Khan at the Garden.
佛罗里达那边怎么样？
What about Florida?
我以为我不能谈佛州的事
I thought we weren't supposed to talk about Florida.
你什么都没干？
So you never got nothing going on?
不是，还没成效，桑尼，我总是运气不佳
No. Nothing ever panned out for me, Sonny. I couldn't catch a break.
- 你什么都做不来  - 我那样说了吗？
- You never got nothing going on? - What did I just say?
桑尼
Sonny.
鲍利，我有一卡车刀片
Paulie, I got a truckload of razor blades.
我要那个有什么用？
What the fuck am I gonna do with razor blades?
嘿，你知道一辆车上能装多少刀片吗？
You know how many razor blades fit in a truck?
我认识一个仓管员说
I got a guy on the inside, works in a warehouse.
有伊朗王的收藏品
Has the art collection of the Shah of Iran.
在哪儿谈？
A sit-down where?
好的
Yeah.
那是红桑的人
That was Sonny Red's guy.
他们要在小意大利谈谈
Wants to have a sit-down in Little Italy.
我被请了
I got sent for.
唐尼，走吧
Donnie, come on.
鲍利，我们用你的车
Paulie, we'll take your car.
红桑尼那老不死的在佛罗里达让我难堪
That cocksucker Sonny Red, he rubbed my nose in Florida
就因为有内鬼！
because of a fucking rat!
得了吧
Forget about it.
唐尼，你坐前面
Donnie, you ride up front.
知道怎样对付内鬼吧，老左？
You know what to do when you find that rat, right, Left?
我已经知道是谁了
Could be I found him already.
去哪儿，桑尼？小意大利区吗？
So where we headed, Sonny? Little Italy?
我们的人说他们要先去别处，明白吗？
Our guy says they got a little stop to make first. You know what I mean?
走吧
Let's go.
你要去哪儿？待在车里
Where are you going? Wait in the car.
好了走吧
All right. Come on.
我们还要回到市中心的
We still got to get downtown.
- 还有多远？  - 我把他们放在洗衣房里了
- How long is this gonna take? - I got them in the drain in the laundry room.
- 点22口径的吗？  - 布诺说你用9毫米的
- The.22s? - Bruno said you want the 9mm.
- 是的，那家伙在哪儿？  - 是啊
- Meanwhile, where the fuck is he? - Yeah.
也许在跟一些比他还丑的婆娘上床
In bed with some broad with more hair on her lip than he's got on his head.
- 是你儿子  - 别提这个
- He's your kid. - Don't remind me. Come on.
你认为很好笑是吗？我不觉得
You think that's funny? I don't think that's so funny.
那好吧
All right.
- 你又不爱听了  - 我不觉得好笑
- You don't want to listen. - I don't think that's funny.
- 做儿子的应该尊重父亲  - 回答我，你觉得好笑吗？
- A son should respect his father, capisce? - Answer me. You think that's funny?
该死，里面灯坏了，当心点走
Shit, the bulb is out. Watch your step, guys.
别冒出个蜘蛛把我吓死才好
Big fucking surprise from a fucking spider.
对，黑桑那家伙等会要被吓死了
Yeah, nothing like the surprise Sonny Black is gonna get.
- 完全正确  - 这里一枪
- You can say that again. - Put one right here.
他做梦也想不到
He'll never know what hit him.
- 一点不错  - 他绝对不知道谁打了他
- Goddamn right. - He's never gonna know what hit him.
- 我会打他脑子 - 天哪！不！
- I'll blow his brains right there. - Jesus! No!
布诺！
Bruno!
快来！快来！把他弄开！
Okay, come on! Get him off!
- 桑尼！  - 把他弄开！
- Sonny! - Get him off of me!
抓住我的手
Take my arm. Take my hand.
天哪！
Jesus Christ.
鲍利，去叫唐尼
Paulie, go get Donnie.
什么事？
What's going on?
- 里面没事吧？  - 什么？
- Is everything all right? - What?
里面没事吧？
Is everything all right?
下车
Get out.
下去
Get down there.
想要称王还轮不到他们
The meek want to inherit the earth, they're gonna have to get in fucking line.
看这是什么
Look what I found.
不是他们就是我们
Them or us.
尼克，你去锯大的
Nicky, you got Big Trin.
- 我？我要岔气的  - 你闭嘴
- Trin? I'll get a hernia. - Shut the fuck up.
唐尼会帮你
Donnie's gonna help you.
过来，唐尼
Come on, Donnie.
帮我锯这肥猪
Help me fillet this fat fuck.
好了，好了
All right, all right. Come on.
动手吧
We got work to do.
佛罗里达有人告密，唐尼
There was a rat in Florida, Donnie.
不是尼克
Nicky wasn't a rat.
别提名字
You don't mention his name, all right?
谈事情的时候别提名字
That's what we said. We don't mention his name.
你怎么说都行，老左
Yeah. Tell yourself whatever you have to, Left.
我不是在跟自己说
I'm not telling myself.
- 你也在，你也看到了  - 杀了认识二十年的人
- You was down there. You have eyes. - Twenty years you know a guy.
你还能悠闲的坐在这里
You fuck him, whack him out, just like that? Over a lounge?
- 你真行啊  - 他私下
- That's beautiful. - The man held out.
背着老板搞鬼
He held out on a coke deal.
这是两码事
What does one thing got to do with the other?
这点也足够让他被做了
He could have got whacked out just for that, for your information.
- 佛州没有内鬼  - 有
- There wasn't a rat in Florida. - There was a rat.
里基搞砸是因为他没有打通关系
There was not a rat in Florida. Richie fucked up paying off the cops.
你凭什么说是里基搞砸的
What do you mean Richie fucked up?
这就是为什么酒吧被捣的原因 因为里基没有摆平该死的警察
That's why the club got busted. Richie didn't pay off the fucking cops.
尼克和这事无关
Nicky didn't have anything to do with it.
叫你别提名字，这是规矩
You don't mention his name. That's the rules.
- 操他妈的规矩！ - 这可是行规，唐尼！
- Fuck the rules. - That's the rules, Donnie.
说他的名字！
Say his name.
- 来啊！  - 说出他的名字
- Come on. - Say his name.
说啊
Come on. Nicky.
说尼克！
Say Nicky.
你不敢说是因为我是对的
You can't say his name because you know that I'm fucking right.
说啊！说尼克！
Say it! Say Nicky!
说他妈的名字
Say his fucking name!
尼克是内鬼，因为黑桑说他是
Nicky was a rat because Sonny Black says he was a rat.
我他妈是谁？
Who the fuck am I?
我是谁？我就像…
Who am I?
轮子的刹车片
I'm a spoke on a wheel.
他也是，你也是
And so was he, and so are you.
别老踩着刹车了
Quit riding the fucking brake.
老板，老板
You the boss. You the boss, Boss.
- 他看起来不错  - 黑桑
- He looks good, huh? - Sonny Black.
恭喜你，桑尼！
Congratulations, Sonny!
老板
Boss!
- 桑尼，恭喜！ - 恭喜
- Sonny. Congratulations, Sonny. - Congratulations.
- 天哪  - 没事，玛吉
- Oh, God! - No, everything's okay, Maggie.
是吗？没事你们来干什么？
Yeah? If everything's okay, what are you doing here?
介意我进去谈吗，皮斯顿太太？
Mind if we come inside, Mrs. Pistone?
我不知道，看情况了
I'm not sure. That depends.
从那时起，他变得疯疯癫癫了
At that point, he became hysterical.
他觉得局子对他被查税负有责任
As if the Bureau were responsible for this audit.
- 其实，也差不太多…  - 你们想没想过给他加薪？
- Whereas, well, self-evidently... - Did you ever think of giving him a raise?
唯一给他加薪的办法是升职
The only way to give him a raise would be to upgrade him.
是
Yeah.
GS-14是主管级别，玛姬
GS-14 is a supervisor, Maggie.
原来他是主管了
So he's a supervisor.
但是他是卧底工作，手下没有人
But he's undercover. He's not supervising anyone.
问题在于，那是最后一次联系到他时的状况
The point is, that's the last time we heard from him.
标准程序是他每天要向我们汇报
Standard procedure is that he is to check in with us every day.
若是中断一两天也没事…
Maybe he might miss a day or two here and there, but...
- 但这已经是三个星期了  - 你告诉我
- It was three weeks ago. - I want you to tell me
我丈夫在哪儿
where my husband is.
我有权要你们告诉我
I demand that you tell me where my husband is!
- 我们也不知道  - 若他跟你联系
- We can't tell you because we don't know. - If he gets in touch with you,
请你跟他讲明
you have got to try to talk sense into him.
皮斯顿太太，请你协助我们
Mrs. Pistone, please help us here.
- 你要我协助你们？  - 是的
- You want me to help you out? - Yes.
要我协助榨干了我丈夫的联邦调查局？
You want me to help out the FBI that used my husband and sucked him dry,
帮你们的领导升官
so that a bunch of supervisors could become SACs
也让检察官升为法官
and prosecutors could become judges and assholes like you
然后你们这些混蛋就可以升为主管？
could get promoted to GS-16?
玛姬，别这样，不是那个意思
Maggie, come on. You don't mean that.
我来告诉你，我希望他反叛
Let me tell you something. I hope he crossed over.
皮斯顿女士，乔打入的黑手党发生了家族内战
Mrs. Pistone, there is a war going on in the Mafia family where Joe is undercover.
内战中三个敌对的头目被杀
Three leaders of a rival faction have been murdered.
他参与了火拼，不是以探员的身份
He's right in the line of fire. Not because he's one of us,
而是以黑帮的身份
because he's one of them.
并且成为他们的头目之一
Who he's with and who he's close to, they're all the top dogs now.
这是我们始料不及的
It's just not a problem we anticipated.
我们要把他挽救出来
We have got to pull him out.
你要跟他谈谈，他会听你的
You have got to talk to him. He'll listen to you.
你们是这样想的吗？
You think so?
他一周前回来过
He was here a week ago.
他悄悄摸进来时我已经睡了
He snuck into the house after I was asleep.
他没有惊醒我，连句好也没问
And he didn't even wake me up, didn't even say hello to me.
他拿了件运动服就走了
He came to get his sport coat.
- 我们出去走走  - 好的
- Let's take a walk. - All right.
嘿，老左，去哪儿？
Left, what are we doing?
边走边谈吧，附近人多眼杂
We're gonna walk and talk. We got too many eyes around here.
是这样，唐尼，红桑的儿子布诺不见了
Here it is, Donnie. Sonny Red's kid, Bruno. He's disappeared.
一天不把他找回来
Now, as long as he's on the loose,
我们就一天不安全
ain't none of us safe.
- 懂吗？  - 是的
- Right? - Yeah.
没有那家伙的消息吗？
You got no idea where the guy is?
那家伙是个瘾君子，总会露面的
He's got a nickel-a-day coke habit. He's gonna turn up somewhere.
好在，我们接了这事
Anyway, we got the contract.
这事如果干的好
Now, this thing gets done right,
下次有位置我就推举你
when the books open up, I'm proposing you for membership.
- 懂我意思吗？  - 懂
- You know what that means? - Yeah.
真的？说说看？
Yeah? What?
- 你希望我不能有闪失  - 你总算明白了
- It means I can't fuck it up. - You read my mind.
- 你总算懂了，千万别搞砸  - 我不会的
- You read my mind. You can't fuck it up. - No, I won't fuck it up.
你会有出息的，唐尼
You're gonna be a made guy, Donnie.
明白吗？
Capisce?
是的
Yeah. All right.
来，我们回里面去！
Come on. Let's go back inside!
- 嘿，老左  - 什么事？
- Left. - Yeah, what?
什么事？冻死我了！
What? I'm freezing here!
你还记得那条伯伦特游船吗？
You know that boat you used to have, that Bertram?
- 船？船怎么了？  - 是的
- Boat? What about it? - Yeah, boat.
你看看那要多少钱？
How much is it? A boat like that? How much? What do you think?
买条那种二手船大概三十万吧
You could get a sports fisherman for maybe 300, used.
你问这个干嘛，唐尼？
Why are you asking me about boats, Donnie?
我只是好奇，我一直这样的
I was just wondering. I was curious, you know.
- 你对船好奇吗？  - 是的
- You're curious about boats? - Yeah.
外面只有10度，我快冻死了！
It's 10 degrees out here. I'm freezing.
我刚和你说这么严肃的话题 而你现在就只想问我船的事？
You're asking me about boats, after what we just said?
嘿，你糊涂了还是怎么的？
You losing your marbles on me or what?
- 不，我很好  - 那就别这样问
- No, I'm all right. - So don't ask questions like that.
- 那样很疯狂，不是吗？ - 好吧
- That's crazy, okay? - Yeah.
你做了这混蛋 然后把他扔在街上，来吧
You hit this cocksucker, and you leave him in the street. Come on.
- 能告诉我你在干什么吗？ - 不，回去睡吧
- You want to tell me what's going on? - Nothing. Go back to bed.
我找点东西，好吗？一会就好
I'm looking for something, all right? I'll be right in.
这样不是办法
That's not gonna work anymore.
包在哪儿？
Where is it?
包里有三十万
There's $300,000 in that bag.
你怎会知道包里有东西的？
How do you know what's in that bag?
我数过了
I counted it.
- 是吗？  - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 数出来？  - 是的
- You counted it? - Yeah.
你说数了是什么意思？那和你没关
What do you mean, you counted it? It's none of your business.
不是我的生意？ 这是我的房子，谁说不关我的事？
Not my business? It's in my house. Who'd ever believe it wasn't my business?
玛吉，给我那该死的包！
I want that fucking bag, Maggie.
拿不到那包里的30万元，FBI的人不会走的
FBI men do not walk around with $300,000 in a bag.
- 乔，你会被抓去会坐牢的  - 闭嘴，没人会坐牢
- Joe, you could go to jail for this. - Shut the fuck up. Nobody's going to jail.
你不为你孩子想想吗？
Did you think about your children for a second?
- 你不懂怎么回事  - 我不懂？
- You have no idea what you're talking about. - I don't?
- 那包是别人的  - 是吗？谁的？
- The bag belongs to somebody else. - Does it? Who?
- 这包是谁的？  - 我最好的一个倒霉伙计
- Whose bag is it, Joe? - One of my best... Just some fucked-up guy.
- 哪个倒霉蛋会要三十万？  - 那包在哪儿？
- A fucked-up guy needs $300,000? - Yeah, right. Where's the goddamn bag?
你像他们一样了，你知道吗？
You're becoming like them, you know that?
你知道我是怎么过日子的吗？
Did you ever once ask yourself how I make it through my days?
我当我自己是寡妇…
I pretend I'm a widow
抱着奖章和回忆过日子
with medals and scrapbooks and memories.
我当你已经死了
I pretend you're dead.
那就是我的生活
That's how my life makes sense to me.
你走吧，离我远点
Just go away. Stay away.
天！我这样爱你，你却如此恨我？
God, why do you hate me when I love you so much?
你以为我恨你？
You think I hate you?
我不恨你
I don't hate you.
是这份工作逼我这样
This job is eating me alive.
没有丝毫的喘息
I can't breathe anymore.
如果我不出现，老左就没命了
And if I come out, this guy Lefty dies.
他们会杀了他，因为是他担保的我
They're gonna kill him, because he vouched for me,
是他在护着我
because he stood up for me.
我天天跟他在一起
I live with that every day.
我要不管等于亲手杀了他，懂吗？
That's the same thing as if I put the bullet in his head myself, you understand?
我花了这么多年想做回一个好人
I spent all these years trying to be the good guy.
清白干净的人
You know, the man in the white fucking hat.
为了什么？
For what?
什么都不为
For nothing.
我不是变得像他们，玛姬，我根本就是他们！
I'm not becoming like them, Maggie. I am them.
老左？唐尼
Left? Donnie.
是唐尼，你在哪儿，唐尼？
Donnie? Where you been?
你听着
Yeah, look...
- 我要见你  - 正好，你快来
- I gotta see you. - You're right, you gotta see me.
- 我们发现红桑的儿子了  - 布诺？
- We found Sonny Red's kid. - Bruno?
是的，他在斯顿岛的一条小船上
Yeah, he's on a boat on Staten Island.
- 我来接你  - 没时间了，唐尼
- I'll pick you up. - We don't have time, Donnie.
- 我们到那儿见 - 好的
- You meet me there. - Okay.
布诺在那儿，他就在码头的那头
Bruno's here. He's down the end of the pier.
我们要等一会儿，等他开始享受
We'll wait here a minute while he has his drink.
等他困了
Let him get a little sleepy.
- 我也困了  - 他的船在哪儿？
- I'm getting a little sleepy myself. - How's his boat?
- 船？  - 是的
- The boat? - Yeah.
好了
Nice.
得了吧，我最了解船
Forget about it. One thing I know is boats.
我想揍他一顿，把他扔到水里，把船抢过来
I'd like to pop him, throw him in the water, take the fucking boat.
以前你怎么说的？再有机会弄到那船…
Remember you said a couple of times how if you had that Bertram again,
你会带安妮特去码头，上船就走
you'd drive down to the pier with Annette and just go?
还记得吗？到天涯海角，谁也找不到
Remember you said that? North, south, east, west, nobody'd ever find you.
那是以前了，别提以前的事
That was before. Don't remind me about that now.
- 我只是想说…  - 我不愿意再去想那事
- Yeah, but I'm just saying... - I don't want to think about that.
那你想过吗？
Did you mean it?
想？
Mean it?
我是洛克菲勒？我要买一艘船？
Who am I? Rockefeller? I'm gonna go buy a boat?
- 假如行呢，老左？  - 什么假如
- I'm saying, what if, Left? - What if.
假如…
What if...
我是说假如我手上有些东西，一些珠宝
I mean, I got a couple of things going on the side. A couple of jewel things.
也许我就能帮你搞到钱
Maybe I could get that kind of money for you.
你想挣钱替我买条船？
You're gonna find money for me to get a boat?
- 也许  - 也许？
- Maybe. - Yeah?
那说明你很慷慨，唐尼
That would be real generous of you, Donnie.
那我现在就把一袋钱给你呢？
What if I could hand you a bagful of money right now?
知道我在说什么吗？
You know what I'm saying?
你可以脱离这种生活
You could leave this life.
你自己说过，老左，假如你不能跳出来
You said it yourself, if you don't move up,
每天都会有同样的压力
every day you're looking over your shoulder.
你不知道会发生什么？
You don't know what's gonna happen.
- 唐尼，你听我说  - 少废话！
- Donnie, listen to me. - No more bullshit.
我说该结束这种生活了，老左
Get out of this life is what I'm saying, Left.
- 我想给你看一些东西，唐尼  - 什么东西
- I'm gonna show you something, Donnie. - What?
我要你非常仔细的看
I want you to look at it very carefully.
然后再认真想想
And then I want you to think very carefully
你曾对我说的话
about what you say to me.
这是一艘FBI的船，唐尼
That's a Federal boat, Donnie.
- 我不认为那是同一条船  - 那是同一条船
- I really don't think that's the same boat... - That's the same boat.
我名字就在上面，“左撇子”
It's got the name on it, The Left Hand.
我名字一样
It's like my name.
就是那条阿巴斯康
That's that Abscam boat.
你认为我知那是FBI的船？
You think I knew that was a Federal boat?
你认为我是卧底？
You think I'm a fucking rat?
我让你去我家多少次了？
How many times I have you into my own house?
至少每周两次，怎么了？
Twice a week, at least. Why?
说得对，“至少”
There it is, "At least."
- 我弄给你吃  - 是的
- I cook for you. - Yeah.
有钱的时候，分给你用…
If ever I had any money, I'd give you.
虽然我穷…但我有钱的时候…
I never had any money. But if ever I had...
我有一百，会分你五十，对吧？
$100 in my pocket, I gave you $50, right?
- 算，是吧  - 如果你是卧底…
- Yeah, you did. - If you're a rat...
如果你真是卧底，我就是黑帮史上最大的傻瓜
If you're a rat, then I'm the biggest fucking mutt in the history of the Mafia.
老左，如果那真是FBI的船
Even if this thing is a Federal boat, Left,
也是他们搞了其他人
they scam all these other people. They didn't scam us.
你明白我的意思吗？
You know what I'm saying?
我们去了，玩爽了，而且我们也脱身了
We went. We had a great party. We walked away from it.
你怎么知道我们真的脱身了
How do you know that we walked away from it?
我们不是正坐在这儿吗？
We're sitting here, right?
他们想算计我们，但是被我们耍了
So they tried to outsmart us, but we outsmarted them.
我们打败了那些探员
We beat the agents.
你应该相信我
You gotta believe me.
那好
Okay.
咱们去做事吧
Let's go do this work.
先做完再说
Get this over with.
用两个手指按在这里，就像按按钮
Two in back of the ear. Like pushing a button.
叭，叭，就这样
Bing, bing. That's it.
- 好的  - 别缩手缩脚
- Yeah. - Don't freeze up.
- 别缩手缩脚好吗？  - 不会的
- You gonna freeze up? - No.
- 很多人会这样  - 我没问题的
- A lot of guys freeze up. - I'll be all right.
我说了你是卧底吗？ 我不敢相信你居然提这事
Did I say you was a rat? I can't believe you brought that up.
得了吧，老左
Come on. Forget about it, Left.
我从没说你是卧底
I never said you was a rat.
我是你的好朋友
I'm your best friend.
来吧，咱们动手吧
Come on. Let's go do this thing.
快动手啊！唐尼
Come on, Donnie. Come on.
快下手！唐尼
Gotta do it, Don.
快！唐尼！
Come on, Don.
快点！
Now!
动手啊！
Come on.
FBI！都别动！
FBI! Freeze!
妈的！
Shit!
别说！什么也别说！唐尼！ 什么也别说！唐尼！
Don't say nothing, Donnie. Don't say nothing to them.
什么也别说！唐尼！
Don't tell them nothing, Donnie!
Donnie, don't say nothing!
- 结束了 - 滚！还没有！
- It's over. - Fuck you, it's not over. I'm not coming out.
在那里呆上二十四小时就没事了
There'll be a mouthpiece there in 24 hours! Donnie, you're all right!
- 操！  - 小子！你完了
- Shit! - It's over, man!
什么也别说，唐尼！
Don't say nothing to them, Donnie!
结束了，乔
It's over, Joe.
你们认识的这个唐尼·布拉斯科 那不是他的真名
You've known this guy as Donnie Brasco. That's not his real name.
其实，他是FBI探员
Truth is, he's been an FBI agent all along.
有什么想说的话，就来找我吧
You can contact me here if you want to talk.
你们相信这些家伙的话吗？
Can you believe those fucking guys?
唐尼不可能是特工
There's no way Donnie's an agent.
真是一派胡言，是吗？
It's a nice fucking bluff, huh?
那条船是个圈套，他们安排好的
That boat was a set-up. They set the boat up.
是吗？想让我们以为他是卧底
See? Then we think Donnie's a rat.
差点让我上当
Almost had me going,
如果你不了解唐尼的话
if you didn't know Donnie.
是的，如果你不了解唐尼的话
Right, if I didn't know Donnie.
鬣狗杀害了很多年幼的猎豹
Hyenas kill many young cheetahs
数量众多的鬣狗甚至能打败雌豹并攻击幼崽
and more than one could overpower the mother and turn on the cubs.
喂？
Yeah?
好吧
Yeah. All right.
好吧，就这样
All right. Okay.
是我的吗？
Was that for me?
不是，要去看望一个朋友
No. It was a guy I got to go see.
- 这么晚还要出去吗？  - 没办法
- So late? - What am I gonna do?
谁知道这些人怎么回事？
Who knows with these people?
- 宝贝，不用等我  - 不等吗？
- Honey, don't wait up for me tonight. - No?
我不知道要去多久
I don't know how long I'm gonna be.
你听着
And listen to me.
如果唐尼打电话来
If Donnie calls
你告诉他…
tell him
如果确有其人的话
if it was going to be anyone,
我很高兴是他，好吗？
I'm glad it was him, all right?
你看上去真迷人
Look how beautiful you look.
- 再见  - 再见，本
- Goodbye. - Bye, Ben.
对不起，皮斯顿太太
Excuse me, Mrs. Pistone.
请坐
Have a seat.
- 为表彰探员乔…  - 只有三十秒
- "To Special Agent Joseph..." - Thirty seconds, sir.
乔瑟夫·D·皮斯顿所作出的突出贡献
"Joseph D. Pistone, in grateful recognition for meritorious service."
请允许我特颁发奖章和五百元奖金
Allow me to present you with this medal and this check for $500.
支票举高点
Hold the check up.
- 恭喜你，孩子  - 恭喜你，乔
- Congratulations again, son. - Congratulations, Joe.
- 太太，请你照顾好他  - 我会的
- Ma'am, take good care of him. - I will.
皮斯顿太太
Mrs. Pistone.
都过去了
It's over.
来吧，宝贝，回家吧
Come on, honey. Come home.
根据乔·皮斯顿搜集到的证据
法庭对二百多人提出指控
一百多人被定罪
探员乔瑟夫·皮斯顿和妻子从此隐姓埋名
至今还有人悬赏五十万要他性命